梦工厂电影公司
派拉蒙影业
维亚康姆旗下公司
梦工厂影片公司
派拉蒙电影公司
联合出品
协助出品
孩之宝
地球  人类的发源地
Earth. Birth place of the human race.
人类和我们非常相似
A species much like our own.
心怀慈悲
Capable of great compassion...
公元前17,000年
也充满了暴力
and great violence.
在我们试图保护人类的同时
For in our quest to protect the humans,
一个更大的秘密昭然若揭
a deeper revelation dawns.
我们曾有过交集
Our worlds have met before.
这里  在这里
Here, here.
变 形 金 刚
第 二 部
中国  上海  今日22:14
上海最新消息
Breaking news at Shanghai.
上海市中心发生了一起毒气泄露事件
There's been a major toxic spill on the Shanghai central district.
-今天市民...  -今天
- Citizens today... - For today,
为您报道此次事态的进展
our topic is a developing story for you,
我们会随时报道最新消息
we will bring you any new information as we get it...
五角大楼 核心基地指挥部
-现在情况怎样  -直升机正接近目标
- What's the status? - C-hawk's approaching target.
长官  还有三分钟疏散才能结束
Three minutes until evacuation's complete, sir.
中国领空方圆一英里已经封锁
Chinese airspace has been locked and sealed. One mile radius.
很好  命令基地部队行动
Alright, give Nest team the go.
黑鹰  可以着陆
Black hawks, clear to land.
叮铃铃  出来吃冰激淋
Ding-a-ling, come out and get your ice cream
坏蛋们出来准备挨鞭子
Any bad robot out there better get ready for ass-whooping.
█
刹车和挡泥板：汽车人成员
老式冰激凌卡车
在过去的两年里  新生代博派的先遣队
For the last two years, an advanced team of new autobots
在我的带领下来到地球避难
has taken refuge here under my command.
阿尔西  准备出发
Arcees, get ready to launch.
我们已经整装待发
We're locked and loaded.
同时  我们和人类结盟
Together, we form an alliance with the humans.
他们是一群秘密又勇敢的战士
A secret, a brave squad of soldiers.
好了  就到这里
Alright, that's enough.
媒体报道说是有毒物质泄露
Time discovered story in this one is toxic spill.
他们清空这片区域方便搜救
They had to evac the area for search and rescue.
这个办法让我们在8个月内消灭6个敌人
This makes six enemy contacts in eight months.
我们要保证这次行动不被大众知道
We gotta make sure this one does not get out the public axe
所以严格保密
So keep it tight.
这支秘密部队代号基地
A classified strike team called Nest.
我们搜寻剩余的死敌霸天虎
We hunt for what remains of our Decepticon foes,
他们隐藏在世界上不同国家
hiding in different countries around the globe.
根据反射波指示飞往阿尔法地区
Rolling alpha through echo now.
好了  铁皮
Alright, Ironhide.
我们侦测到敌人反射波逃窜
We got echo's vamos.
到那堆东西那里  2点方向
To the stacks. Two o'clock.
█
铁皮：汽车人成员
通用GMG中型商用车
他在这儿
He's here.
我嗅到了
I smell him.
很近了  正在接近
It's close. It's heading closer.
不
Oh, no.
怎么了
How are ya?
有三个敌人
It's three ripple.
好了  各位  镇定
Alright, everybody, be steady.
我们就在它近前
We're right on top of it.
█
破坏者：霸天虎成员
特雷克斯矿用液压挖土机
请求支援
Ease on fire.
黑豹1号  立即火力支援
Panther one. Requesting fire mission now!
武装直升机已就位  正在路上
Gunships on station. Rolling hot.
我们刚路遇一名霸天虎
We intersected a Decepticon.
█
破坏者：霸天虎成员
奥迪R8跑车
阿尔西姐妹  目标向你们去了
Arcee twins, target coming your way.
当心
Watch out!
█
阿尔西姐妹：汽车人成员
女性变形金刚摩托车
我搞砸了  还好  没大事
I screwed that up. I'm okay, I'm alright.
伙计  这样可部队  你什么毛病
This is kinda bad, man. What's wrong with you?
里面有三个
Three insides white.
█
横炮：汽车人成员
考维特黄貂鱼百年概念跑车
明白  马上搞定
Clear and fast.
我真他妈强
Damn, I'm good.
空中支援  我们需要大个子空降上场
Air support, we need big booter delivered and dropped now.
五  四  三  二  一
Dropping in five, four, three, two, one.
█
擎天柱：汽车人首领
彼得比尔特389牵引卡车头
博派众将  我来追他
Autobots, I'm in pursuit.
给我靠边
Pull over.
蠢货霸天虎
Punk-ass Decepticon,
有什么遗言吗
Any last words?
这个星球不是你说了算
This is not your planet to rule.
堕落金刚会卷土重来
The fallen shall rise again.
听起来挺麻烦
That doesn't sound good.
但不是今天
Not today.
快点  出发了  都出来了
Come on, let's go. All hands on deck.
弗兰克  魔咒  快出来
Frankie, Mojo, out.
快点  小伙子  我们得准时
Come on, kiddo, We're on a schedule here.
等等  老爸  为什么急着撵我走啊
Slow down, dad. Why are you in such a hurry to get rid of me, huh?
你已经把我的房间租出去了吗
Did you rent the room out?
没有  我对你的房间另有打算
No, I got other ideas for your room
我会把它改造成一个家庭影院
And it rhymes with home theater.
看我找到了什么  你小时候婴儿鞋
Look what I found. It's your little baby booties.
妈妈...
Oh, ma...
我的宝贝儿子  真不舍得你走
Oh my little baby, booty boy, you can't go.
看到了吗  老爸
You see this? Dad
亲生儿子就要踏入社会了
That's how you're supposed to react
这才是你应该有的反应
when you free your loins does not uncool the world to pep for himself,
行吧
Okay?
行  我的心都碎了 上大学真郁闷
Yeah, my heart broke. please treat it about college, bummer.
你假期都要回来啊
You have to come home every holiday,
小的假期也要回来啊
Not just big ones.
万圣节也要回来啊
You have to come home for Halloween.
我万圣节回不来  妈妈
I can't come home for Halloween, mom.
-我们去看你  -不  我们哪儿也不去
- We'll come to you. - No, we're not going anywhere.
-我们会打扮好去的  -不不  你不能这样
- You dress up, we'll be in costumes. - You-you can't do that.
能不能让你儿子喘口气  不要一直哭
Would you let the kid breathe, for crying out loud?
快点  去装行李
Come on, go, pack!
这样你可没法打包一个月的行李
There's no way you can packed For a month long trip.
快点  快点  我们要走了
Come on! Chop-chop. Let's go!
快点动  小妞儿
March, young lady.
-老爸  -我喜欢你叫我小妞儿
- Oh, oh, dad! - I love you when you call me young lady.
你这老不正经的
you dirty, old man.
你还没见识别的呢
Nah, you ain't seen nothing yet.
-老爸  老爸  哇  -怎么啦
- Dad, dad, dad, whoa! - What?
老爸  我还在这儿看着呢  注意场合
I'm watching what you're doing, dad. It's not a rap video.
不过就像教练那样而已  你知道的
Just like a coach thing, you know.
刚才你的动作真让我起鸡皮疙瘩  老爸
That's a really creepy move just now, dad.
听着  你是英雄
Look, you're the hero, uh...
我和你妈妈真的为你感到骄傲
Your mother and me are really, really proud of you.
你是威特维基家第一个上大学的
You're the first Witwiky ever to go to college.
我又想哭了  真是的
Now I'm crying again. This sucks!
你会没事的  老妈
You're gonna be okay, ma.
对她来说  你知道的  很难接受
Now this is going to be, uh....You know, hard for her to...
自己的儿子长大了
Accept that her boy's all grown up, you know.
要离开去独自闯世界
Going out to handle the world on its own.
-你还好吗  爸爸  -没事
- You okay, pop? - yeah.
魔咒别欺负弗兰克
Mojo, no dominating Frankie!
滚沙发下面去  你这下流坯子
Get the hell of the couch, ya filthy beasts!
哇
Wow.
这场景大学里也很常见
You see a lot of that in college too.
你说什么啊  老爸
What are you talking about, dad?
那里会有很多女孩子
There's gonna be a lot of women there.
可我是一个专情的人
Yeah, well, I'm the one-woman kind of guy.
米凯拉是很好
Look, Mikaela is the greatest,
可你们要给彼此空间来发展  明白吗
But you gotta give each other room to grow, okay?
你们和同龄的其他伴侣没什么差别
You're no different than any other couple your age.
但我们一起发现过外星人
Till we discovered an alien race together.
看你这个理由还能撑多久
How long are you gonna be riding that scooter?
老爸  我知道其他人会怎样
Dad, listen, I know the others.
我们是例外  知道吗
We're the exception, okay?
等会儿...
Wait a second...
-看看  这是谁啊  -两星期以后  就是另一个女孩子打给你了
- Oh, who could that be? - Two weeks, it could be Muffy.
嘿  美人
Hey, beautiful.
-我要和你分手  山姆  -真的吗
- I'm breaking up with you, Sam. - Really?
你确定  我听到过你这样说过很多次了
Sure? I hear a lot of conviction.
这次是认真的  明白吗
Well, I am, okay?
所以没有理由我再来送别你了
So there's no reason for me to come say goodbye to you.
你这次听起来很认真啊
Wow, you almost sounded serious that time.
知道吗
Guess what?
我要给你一套异地恋爱装备
I made you a long-distance relationship kit.
我给你弄了个摄像头  我们就能随时视频聊天
Yeah, I got you a webcam so we can chat 24 for 7.
任何时候我都在你身边
All Witwicky all the time.
还有些纪念品
I got you a couple of souveniers
电话里不能和你说
That you bet that cannot be mentioned on cellphone.
还有一些录音  蜡烛什么的
Some mixes and candles and stuff...
听起来不错  我都等不及了
Sounds cute, I can't wait.
好的  嘿
Oh, hey!
上次作战的那件破上衣要吗
You want the infamous d-day shirt?
你还留着那些又破又脏的衣服啊
You kept your nasty, shredded clothes?
那是当然  我一直留着的  米凯拉
Yeah, of course I kept it, Mikaela.
这可是我的战袍  还沾着我的血呢
It's like my superbowl jersey. I bled in this thing.
你相当自信啊
Wow, you're pretty confident, huh?
不  当然不是
No, it's not that.
只是我的低自尊心空前高涨了一次
It's just that my low self-esteem's at an all-time high.
你以为那盒纪念品就能留住我吗
Do you think your little box of souveniers is gonna keep me from leaving you?
你应该和我一起走的
You really should come with me,
校园里有廉价的公寓出租
They got cheap apartments in campus.
现在是不可能的
Well, that's not gonna happen
除非我那个刚从监狱里出来长不大的爸爸能独立
Until I get my man child father rushed out of prison back on his feet.
我听见了
I heard that.
你把离合器盖子放哪啦
Where did you put the clutch covers?
凸轮轴旁边
Next to the cam shafts.
我喜欢你说这个词  再和我说一遍
I love it when you say cam shafts. whisper it to me.
凸轮轴
Cam shafts.
我没法恨你
Can I hate you?
这就是威特维奇家的魅力
It's my Witwicky charm.
等会儿  别挂  等一会儿
Wait, hold on. wait, hold on a second.
我想我们是不会分手的
I guess we're not breaking up.
我20分钟以后下班
I'll be over in 20.
米凯拉
Mikaela...
我衬衫里有一小块能量源碎片
I got a sliver of cube stuck on my shirt.
山姆
Sam?
天啊  着火了
Oh god! It's a fire!
老爸  着火了
Dad, we got a fire!
着火了
Fire!
罗恩  你知道我会这么...
Ron, did you know it was gonna be
-这么难受吗  -你能歇会儿吗
- This hard? - C-can you just stop?
-好  行  我歇了  -等等...
- Yeah, okay, I'll stop. - just wait...
-你自己搬吧  -我来  我来...
- You carry this shit. - I'll--I'll...
知道吗  我不想和你一起去任何地方
You know what?  I don't wanna go anywhere with you.
我才不会和你一起去法国
I don't wanna go to France with you.
连街角都不会和你一起去
I don't wanna go around the corner with you.
-好吧  -我只想回家里去
- Alright, fine. - I'm just going back inside.
我会从巴黎打电话给你的
I'll call you from Paris.
什么这么吵啊
What is all the racket?
-那些是什么  -都是厨房电器
- What was that? - It's the whole kitchen!
大黄蜂
Bumblebee!
█
大黄蜂：汽车人成员
2006款雪佛兰卡马洛概念车
快打911
Phone 9-1-1.
大黄蜂  快回车库
Bumblebee! Get in the garage.
- 发生了什么  -你怎么不节制点  伙计
- What the frick is happening?  - What happened to restraint, man?
快回车库  静静的  快点
Just go in the garage, quietly please?
我的妈呀
Holy mother!
天啊
Oh, my god!
-我  -回车库去  马上
- I  - In the garage, now!
停车  警察快来啊
Power's out! Get the cops out!
快点  你们还在等什么
Come on, you guys. what are you waiting for?
我房子着火了
My house is on fire!
-发生了什么  -过来
- What happened? - Come here.
听着  我要你保管这块能量碎片
Listen, I need you to take the cube sliver.
快把它放到你包里
Put it in your purse, right now.
-山姆·威特维奇 -来了  妈妈
- Sam witwicky... - Yes, mom.
-有话和你说  -好的
- A word with you. - Yeah.
-你好  米凯拉  -你好
- Hi, Mikaela. - Hi.
我这儿都烧秃了
I have a bald spot.
-我觉得是炉子太旧了  -我不是好惹的
- An old furnace, I think. - I'm a waffle lier
你走的时候  他也得走
When you go, he goes.
我可不想我车库里有个神经病的外星人
I cannot live with this psychotic alien in my garage.
朱迪  小声点
Judy, shh.
国家机密
National security.
听着  我们保持沉默  他们就会搞定一切
Look, if we stay quiet, they're gonna take care of everything.
就当是政府帮我们装修吧  好吗
Just consider this the official start of a remodel, okay?
好吧  如果政府出钱  我要个游泳池...
Fine. If the government's paying, I want a pool...
-还要个喷泉浴缸  -好的  没问题
- And a hot tub. - Fine. Okay.
我还要在里面裸泳  你不能说个不字
And I'm gonna skinny-dip and you can't say shit about it!
好吧  你知道你就是个麻烦
Yeah, you know you're a trouble.
-他的发声有问题  -他装的
- He's having voice problems. - He's playing it up.
大黄蜂  我想和你说我上大学这事  好吗
Bee, I want to talk to you about the college thing, okay?
太激动动了
I'm so excited
我不能带你一起去
I'm not taking you with me.
我在外面等你
I wanna wait outside, okay?
我本来想早点告诉你的
I wanted to tell you about this earlier.
这样的
It's just that-- you know,
有规定
Here's the thing.
新生不允许有车
Freshmen aren't allowed to have cars.
如果我说了算  我会带你去  可不是  大黄蜂
I know, and if it was up to me, I'd take you with me, but it's not, bee.
你是个汽车人
Look, you're an autobot.
你本不该住在我爸的车库里
You shouldn't be living in my dad's garage.
我是说这里太委屈你了
I mean, you're suffocating in here.
你应该有比这更好的地方
You deserve better than this.
我已经很难受了  伙计
This is hard enough, man,
别再让我难受了  看着我行吗  伙计
Don't make it harder. Can you just look at me, please?
快点  大家伙
Come on, big guy.
护卫工作结束了  你做得很棒
Look, the guardian thing is done, okay? you did your job.
看看  我现在是多么安全
Look, I'm safe now.
你应该回到擎天柱和你其他伙伴中间
You need to go be with Optimus Prime and the others.
我只是想做一个正常人  大黄蜂
I just want to be normal, Bee.
所以我才会上大学
That's why I'm going to college.
我不能再带着你了
I can't do that with you.
这也不会是我最后一次见你  大黄蜂
It's not the last time I'm gonna see you, you know, Bee.
别那样  伙计  这让我难过至死  大黄蜂
Come on, don't do that. Bee. You're killing me, Bee.
但是你永远都是我的第一辆车
But you'll always be my first car.
我爱你  大黄蜂
Love you, Bee.
无论作为国营农场还是纳税人  我们都会得到赔偿的
Between state farm and the taxpayers, we're all taken care of.
-看你都弄脏了  -停下  停下
- You got dirt all over you. - Stop, stop.
-什么啊  -我没事
- What? - It's--I'm okay.
看啊
Well, look.
你觉得没我的帮助你也能在大学取得成功
So you think you can make it through those east coast winners without me?
你是我最珍贵的人
You're like the best thing that ever happened to me.
而且
And?
-我会为你做任何事情  -还有呢
- And I'll do anything for you. - And?
-山姆要表白了  -加油  小伙子
- I think Sam's about to say the l word. - Let's go, kiddo.
真不错  他爸
Nice timing, dad.
我...喜欢你
I... adore you.
这不是我现在想听的词
That's not the word that I wanna hear really now.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
这个词和另外一个是一样的
It's the same word as the other word.
-不一样  -如果我现在一定要说那个词
- It's not the same word. - Look, if I said the other word now,
就是你强迫的  这样没有意义
You forced me to say won't mean anything.
还有  那个词你也没有说过
Plus, you haven't said it either.
所以不要因为没有说那词就冲我发火
So don't get mad at me for not saying it.
好吧  但我还没有说过
Yeah, but I haven't said it
因为一般如果我先说男生就会逃跑
Because guys always run when you say it first.
好吧  其实女孩也是一样的
Yeah, well, so do girls.
特别是  像你这样有很多人追的女孩
Especially, girls like you with options.
那么这就是你留住我的精心计划
So this is all part of your elaborate plan to keep me interested?
可能吧
Can be.
有用吗
Ain't those working?
来吻一下
Have a kiss.
歌名:Never Say Never <永不言不>
我们会在一起的  我保证
We'll make it work, I promise.
█
转轮：霸天虎成员
儿童遥控玩具越野车
那女孩拿着能量块碎片
█
声波：霸天虎成员
轨道太空间谍卫星
全体霸天虎注意  跟着她
Soundwave acknowledges. Pursue her.
夺回碎片
Retrieve it.
秘密基地  迭戈·加西亚岛  印度洋
博派双胞胎  到三号车库报到
Autobot twins, report to hangar three.
不好意思  请让一下
Excuse me, excuse me.
多美妙的一夜  是啊宝贝  车该升级了
Hello. What a night. Yeah, baby, it's upgrade time.
是啊  看这  来吧  我要变这样的
Yes, oh, yeah. Look here. Come on, let me call right here.
我该变得漂亮点了
Time to get my sexy on.
我要绿的  我知道
Green, I know,
我要绿的  我要变绿的
Green is mine, I call green
雪佛兰斯巴克   雪佛兰确克斯
已经是我的
Be my body
-我要绿的  -很疼的  老兄
- I got the green. - That hurt, man.
当然疼了  摔的就是你
It's supposed to hurt. It's an ass kicking.
盖勒威顾问 幸会
Director Galloway, what an honor.
本想带你参观一下
Let me show you around
但你不能进入绝密区
But you gotta be in the classified access list.
现在可以了
I am now.
总统亲自授权  少校
Presidential order, major.
我给你那些神秘的外星朋友带了个信
I got a message for your classified space buddies.
你们在上海的行动搞砸了
You guys made a mess at Shanghai.
这里就是我们和参谋长联系的地方
Alright, so this is where we communicate with the JCS.
这里是博派的车库
And this area serves as the Autobots' hangar.
和参谋长联系上了  少校
Secured line to JCS is up, Major.
美国军用卫星
现在连接五角大楼
Secured line to the pentagon now.
看看上海的行动  真是一团糟
Saw the shanghai op. It was a rough day.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我有重要的情报要直接汇报
We have wintel but I believe warns an immediate debrief.
经过您的允许  不能让您看见他
Now with your permission, I can't let you see him
但我可以让您和博派首领直接通话
But I would like you to hear from the leader of the autobots.
开始吧
Proceed.
看到奇迹了吧
You gotta wonder.
神用自己的形象创造了我们  可谁创造了他
God made us in his image. Who made him?
将军  今年我们联盟已经打退了狂派的6次进攻
General, our alliance has countermanded 6 decepticon incursions this year.
每次都在不同的大洲
Each on a different continent.
很明显  他们在寻找什么东西
They're clearly searching around the world for something.
但昨晚狂派却警告说
But last night's encounter came with a warning
堕落金刚将会卷土重来
The fallen shall rise again.
堕落金刚  什么意思
"The fallen." Meaning what?
不清楚
Original Unknown.
我们变形金刚
They only recorded
唯一的历史记录在火种里
History of our race was contained within the all-spark,
火种被摧毁了  历史也就无人知晓
Lost with its destruction.
我插句话
Excuse me!
如果你们所谓的火种被摧毁了
If this so-called "all-spark", now destroyed,
那为什么敌人不像你想的那样
Why hasn't the enemy left the planet
离开地球
Like you thought they would?
盖勒威顾问  国家安全顾问
Director Galloway, our national security advisor
总统刚刚任命他负责联络
The president just appointed him liasion.
-有点  -我怎么没接到通知
- It's too, uh... - Well, I guess I didn't get that memo.
很抱歉打断您的谈话  将军  不好意思
Forgive the interruption, general. Excuse me, coming through.
不好意思  借过
Excuse me, excuse me...
上次的行动对上海造成了巨大的破坏
After all the damage in Shanghai,
总统
The president is, uh...
不得已声称行动成功
Hard-pressed to say the job's getting done.
根据博派秘密合作议案
Now under the classified alien Autobot cooperation act,
你们同意和我们共享你们的情报
You are agreeing to share your intel with us,
但却没有共享你们的先进装备
But not your advancements in weaponry.
我们已经看到了你们人类好战的本性
We've witnessed your human capacity for war.
共享武器  无疑将是弊大于利
It would absolutely bring more harm than good.
你是谁  凭什么对我们指手画脚
But who are you to judge what's best for us?
恕我直言  我们已经
With all due respect, we've been fighting side-by-side
并肩作战两年多了
In the field for two years.
我们一起出生入死
We've shared blood, sweat and precious metal together.
大兵  你的职责是打仗  不是插话
Soldier, you're paid to shoot; not talk.
用你说
Don't tell me.
而且
And the, uh...
-你们又来了新成员  -冷静
- The newest members of your team... - Easy...
我知道是你向太空发出信息
I understand they arrived here after you sent a message into space.
公开邀请他们来地球
An open invitation to come to earth,
但从未和政府打过招呼
Embedded by no one at the White House.
我得打断一下  盖勒威先生
Let me stop you right there, Mr. Galloway.
审核就在这进行
It was bedded right here.
而且据我所知  论诺克斯少校和他的队伍
And in my experience, the judgement of both Major Lennox and his team,
所做的判断都是准确的
Has always been above reproach.
即便如此  将军  总统认为
Well be that as it may, General, it is the position of the president
眼下的国家安全受到威胁
That when our national security is at stake,
没人能做到完美
No one is above reproach.
来看看我们都知道些什么
Now, what do we know so far?
我们知道  敌人的领袖
We know that the enemy leader,
NBE一号  威震天
Classified NBE-1, Aka Megatron,
已经变成一堆废铁
Is resting in peace
被扔到了劳伦森海沟深处
At the bottom of the Laurentian abyss,
而且它还被声纳监听系统
Surrounded by societs detection nets
和潜艇全天候监控
And a full-time submarine surveillance.
我们还知道
We also know that
你们盟友所谓的火种的唯一碎片
The only remaining piece of your alien all-spark
被保存于全世界最安全的海军基地的
Is locked in an electromagnetic vault,
一个电磁保险库中
Here on one of the most secure naval bases in the world.
狂派们  我们已经找到了火种碎片存放地
Decepticons, we have located the shard.
虽然没有人知道
And since no one...
敌人究竟在寻找什么
Can seem to tell me what the enemy is now after,
但至少有一个明显的答案
Well, there--there's only one clear clusion
就是你们博派
You. The Autobots.
他们是来追杀你们的
They're here to hunt you.
除此之外他们还能为了什么
What's there to hunt for on earth besides that?
堕落金刚将会卷土重来
"The fallen... shall rise again"?
听起来好像是有什么事要发生
Sounds to me like something's coming.
所以我有个问题  如果我们最终决定
So let me ask if we ultimately conclude
只有你们离开我们的地球
That our national security is best served
才能确保地球的安全
By denying you further asylum on our planet,
你们会和平的离开吗
Will you leave peacefully?
自由是你们的权利
Freedom is your right.
如果你们做出决定  我们会尊重你们的要求
If you make that request, we will honor it.
但是在你们的总统决定之前  请问问他
But before your president decides, please ask him this.
如果我们走了  而你们又错了  你们怎么办
What if we leave and you're wrong?
问的好
That's a good question.
上帝啊
Oh, my god,
看看这个地方
Just look at this place!
我觉得自己都变聪明了
I feel smarter already.
罗恩  你闻到了吗
Ron, can you smell it?
是的  一年4万的学费
Yes, smells like $40,000 a year.
真抠门
Okay, Cheapo.
你去吧  我来帮你搬
Go ahead, we'll, uh... we'll get your stuff.
你去看看自己的房间
Just go ahead and check out your room.
你一定是山姆  对吧  我是里奥
You must be Sam, right? I'm Leo.
不好意思我已经占了里面小间
Uh, sorry, I already set up the crib.
你想要这边还是那边
Do you want this side or that side?
-那边吧  -我已经选了那边
- That side. - I already chose that side.
你什么意思  想让我难堪吗
You know what this is? This is the awkward moment.
你一定是想看看我是不是正常
Yeah, so you're trying to see if I'm a normal guy.
我还怕你不正常呢
I'm trying to see if you're a normal guy,
身体正常  没有不良嗜好
Balanced and medicated enough for another coral space.
讲究卫生  别在我睡觉的时候打扰我
Good personal hygiene won't stab me in my sleep.
无犯罪记录  不会偷东西
Good criminal record won't steal anything.
-包括女友  -特别是女友
- Including girlfriends. - Especially girlfriends.
-你有女朋友  -当然
- You got a girlfriend? - I do.
-你呢  -没  没有
- You? - No, not a chance.
喜欢电脑吗
You're a techie?
很好
Sweet.
-沙士其  法比纳  怎么样了  -服务器马上上线了  里奥
- Sharsky, Fassbiner, where we at? - Server's almost online, Leo.
已经连接了
It works up and running.
漂亮  我就想听这个
Beautiful; that's what I like to hear.
-那是沙士其  那是斯巴斯提克  -你好伙计
- That's Sharsky, that's Spastik, - Hey, dude.
我的IT顾问
My i.t. gurus.
欢迎来到我的帝国  活计 真实的世界网站
Welcome to my empire, Bro. Therealeffindeal.com.
我办的  你一定听过
That's me, I'm sure you've heard of it.
-我没听过  -那糟糕了
- No, I haven't. - Well, that sucks.
-是什么网站  -听着
- What is all this for? - See, look...
其实挺俗气的  我想成为少年百万富翁
Call me Gross, I wanna be a baby billionaire.
小猫日历
Kitten calendars.
从这起家的  现在看看我
It's where it started. Look at me now.
人要有梦想  伙计
Got our dreams, bro.
里奥  有个坏消息从上海传来
Leo, we got some bad news in Shanghai.
发在网上  快  快  添料
Post it, baby. go, go, go! ftj, ftj!
-真清楚  -添料是什么意思
- It's clean. - What's ftj?
-给飞机加燃料  -添料  添料
- Fuel the jet, fuel the jet. - Ftj, Ftj.
-就是这  看见了吗  -半个上海啊
- This is it. Did you see that? - Wow. okay, this half of shanghai
官方却称是燃气泄露
Gets rigged when china says gas leak.
肯定是骗人的
Don't believe the hype, bro.
两年前洛杉矶出现的外星机器人也没报道
Just like the alien robots in LA two years ago that everyone covered up.
是啊  我看到了那些机器人
Yeah, I saw these robots and they did this, like,
到处放火  他们从天而降
Firing thing and they came down and twisted this woman
-杀了个女人  -我看是假造的
- And she was like-- - Looks fake to me.
兄弟  不是假造的  网络是真实的
Dude, it's not fake. the internet's pure true.
-视频不会骗人  -看起来就像假造的
- Video doesn't lie. - It looks fake.
没  我亲眼所见  那些机器人像这样
No, man, I've seen them. They are like these, uh, robots...
听着  听着  那都是假的  谁都可以用电脑伪造
Look, look, look, it's fake. Anybody can do on any computer, okay?
当时我不在场
And I wasn't, uh... there.
所以我不能评论或推测
So I can't comment or speculate.
-不  -评论和推测
- Oh, no. - "Comment and speculate"?
我们要被圈养吗
We're supposed to go habitate?
不  听着  别被蒙在鼓里  伙计
No, listen, okay. Don't be sucking the sack, bro.
-什么鼓  -骗人的鼓啊
- Whose sack? - Look, the ball sack.
-你从火星来的吗  伙计  -主流媒体的鼓
- Dude, what kind of tool are you? - Mainstream media sack.
他们在欺骗我们
They're lying to us, alright.
-那些是外星人  -好吧
- It's aliens, man. - Okay, okay.
跟我来
Follow me.
里奥  不好了  我们动手晚了
Uh-oh. uh, Leo. bad news, we just got scooped.
别的网站上已经有视频了
The video's already up on geoboard.
该死的
Damn... no!
我们有一个主要竞争对手  很阴险
Robo-warrior is a main competition, our conspiracy step.
这他妈是我的主意  他偷了
Effing was my effing idea. He stole it.
他访问我的网站  疯狂抄袭稿件
He's been looking to my site and thieving hits for ever!
还有  我看过你的档案
By the way, I read your file.
我穷  你也穷  我们一起致富  如何
I'll poor, you'll poor... we're gonna fix that, alright?
你现在为我工作
You work for me, now.
我为你工作
I work for you now?
难以置信  我上大学的第一天
That's incredible. It's first day of college,
就要供职于一家破网络公司
I got a career, a dinky internet firm,
而且老板还是个如此自大的人
With a boss who is made up of just pure champion stuff.
你在嘲笑我毕生的心血  塞缪尔  是吗
You're mocking my life's work, Samuel? huh?
我警告你  活计
That's your one warning patrolling, Dude.
别惹我  不然我盗了你的帐户
Don't make me that fast.... 'cause I'll do it.
管理员 这房间我住不惯
Hey alright, listen. It's getting a little intense in my room.
-能调换吗  -看你这张脸 312
- can I switch now? - oh, Sad face, 3-12.
不退不换  别老皱着眉头了
No switching, no treating. Let's turn that upside-down, okay?
我们来了
Oh, here we go.
真像像霍格沃茨魔法学校
It's just like Hogwarts.
这里男女混住吗  男女混住
Is this co-ed? This is a co-ed dorm.
你们想见见我的室友吗
Do you guys want to meet my roommates?
-好啊  -他们可都是些大人物
- Yeah. - 'Cause they're real swell guys.
-她是里奥  -我们是他的父母
- Here is Leo. - We're the witwicky.
-我是里奥  -我是朱迪
- I'm Leo. - I'm Judy.
你儿子很棒  真的很棒
Hey, you have a great son. You really do.
你才最乖呢
Oh, well aren't you the sweetest thing?
他真的很乖  老妈
He's real sweet, ma.
顺便问下  你手里拿的什么
What is that in your hand, by the way?
我在保护环境义卖那里买的
Oh, I got this at the bake sale for the environment
那些男孩做的
That those boys were having.
你知道  留辫子的白人
You know, you don't often see white boys
可不多见
With the dreadlocks.
-妈妈  -这可是百分之百的夏威夷
- Mom. - Yeah, it's a 100 percent pure hawaiian
-绿色环保产品  -朱迪  把那个扔了吧
- Green for the environment. - Jud--can you please drop it?
是啊  他们在里面加了大麻
Yeah, then they baked it with reefer in it.
-不可能  -给我
- No, it's canna-- hey! - Please give me.
今天我作主  想吃什么都可以
Hey! It's my cheap day. I can eat whatever I want.
上帝啊  我要疯了  赶紧管管她  老爸
Please god, I'm gonna freak out. Please do something right now, Dad.
-管管她  -好吧  好吧
- Please do something right now. - Okay, okay.
别挡路  你这野小子
Out of my way, you wild hair!
我想吃什么都可以
I can eat all the freaking brownies I want!
不好意思  各位
Sorry, fellas.
不好意思  别客气
I'm sorry and you're welcome.
这里云集全校美女(西班牙语)
我们称这为新人55强
We call it the hot freshmen 55.
沙士其修改了住宿分配系统  调来全部美女
Sharsky hacked campus house and stacked the dorm with pretty beddies.
上帝啊  是她
Oh, my god. It's her.
她来了  她在看我  她在看我
She's coming. She sees me, She sees me.
她是我最喜欢的女孩
She's tight for me on one on my to-do list.
你可不许抢  听见了吗
Do not bird-dog my credit, you hear me?
美女们
Pretty girls.
告诉你  我儿子住在这个房间
Hey, you. My son lives in this dorm.
你该去和他交个朋友
You should go make friends with him,
-他很坏  -幸亏她不是我妈
- He's bad. - Bless she ain't my mama.
他最近才破处的
And he recently had his cherry popped.
他不知道当时我在房间里
He didn't know I was in the house.
我全听到了
I heard it all.
就是他
There he is!
你们能告诉他我说了什么吗
Oh, will you give him my closet?
他的车还是个会说话的机器人
Hey, and his car is a talking robot!
不  那只是个  导航仪
No, like a... like a gps, all-star.
-知道了  -导航仪
- Okay. - All-star.
飞盘
Frisbee. whoo!
不  老爸
No, dad.
老爸  你不能让她满学校的乱跑
Dad, you're just gonna let her run around school.
你没事吧
Are you alright?
给我
Give me.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
朱迪  朱迪  放下  放下
Judy, Judy. Just--Just put it. Just put it.
你得看好你妈妈
You gotta control your mother.
我也不想这样
I wasn't doing this.
教授  只要给我A  做什么都行
Hey, professor. I'd do anything for an A.
没问题  美人
Alright, Grace...
看来我们得上车去了  我们走
Looks like we got some snacks in the car. Let's go.
你拿到那双鞋了吗
Did you get the booties?
是的  爸爸  我拿到了
Yes, dad, I got the booties!
-好吧  好吧  -上帝啊  我大头冲下了
- Alright, Alright. - Oh my god, I'm upside-down!
█
机器狗：霸天虎成员
声波派出的小型机械狗变形体
军事基地
黑狮射线  我是黑狮探戈
Black lion in x-trait. This is black lion in tango.
B14区  有人入侵
Breach in B-14.
快走  快  快
Go, go, go, go, go!
火种碎片不见了
The shard is gone.
干掉他
Take him down!
-开火  -卧倒
- Open fire. - Get down!
第一次聚会是男孩的好机会
The first frat party's the game change of boys,
现在是猎妞时间  准备好参加聚会吧
We're hunting in the wild now, so get your game faces on.
我不能待太久  我还要和女友视频约会
I can't stay long, I have a webcam date with my girlfriend.
-真酷啊  -才不呢
- That's so cool. - No, it's not.
你回去抱着笔记本相会吧
While you are making up with his Macbook,
今晚我要疯个痛快
I'm gonna be dating my spitzy, freaky freak on.
-咱们走  -她真辣
- Let's roll. - She's hot.
我们  我们去泡妞了
We're, uh... we're hunting.
-再见亲爱的  -再见  老爸
- See you, darling. - Bye, dad.
好了
Okay.
这是我们第一次联线  以前还从没做过
This is our first live chat date. Never done it before.
我还真有点紧张
I'm kind of nervous.
-你还好吧  -不
- Are you okay? - No, uh...
我就是拿个垫杯子的餐巾
I was getting a napkin for my drink.
谢谢  干杯
Thanks. Cheers!
-你是山姆  对吧  -是
- You're Sam, right? - Yeah.
我想跳舞
I wanna dance.
你喜欢跳舞
Like--like dancing?
像情侣那样吗
Like a pairing? like a duo, like a coupling?
我已经有女朋友了
'cause I'm in a permanently, semi--
-我有女朋友了  -放松
- I'm in a relationship, kind of. - Oh, relax.
我只是想找点乐子
I just want to have some fun.
找乐子  好吧
Oh, just some fun? oh yeah, okay.
咱们玩跳棋吧  你可以坐那边
Let's play some checkers. You can sit over there, and, uh...
-我的天  -这样吧  今晚
- oh my god. - So how about tonight,
我假装是你女朋友  你假装是我男朋友
You pretend I'm your girlfriend and I pretend that you're my boyfriend.
山姆不在线
谁把个破黄色卡马洛跑车停在门外了
Hey! Who broke the frickin' yellow camaro?
车子还发动着
Huh? There's a car on the run.
你来干吗
What are you doing?
休斯顿  我们有麻烦了
Houston, we have a problem.
-什么麻烦  -新来的
- What is it? - freshman!
-是  -草坪上的车是你的吗
- Yeah. - Is that your car on our bushes?
不  是我朋友的  他刚去
No, there's a friend of mine who just went to a...
去给你拿限量版衬衫
Who went to get you a tighter shirt.
没什么限量版衬衫  我们查过了
There isn't a tighter shirt. We checked.
想让我用脚踢你屁股吗
Now how about I park my foot in your ass?
你穿几码鞋
What size shoe do you wear?
-你是不是欠揍  -慢着  慢着
- yeah, oh, you ain't-- - hold on, hold-- whoa!
你真要找揍
Are you--are you want to try?
我现在就把它开走
I'm gonna back it up right now.
快开走
Get it out of here.
你有车
You have a ride?
居然不告诉我们
Bro, why you holding onto us?
我们才认识了17个小时
I've only known you 17 hours.
这会彻底改变我们的生活
This is gonna really change our lives.
你不明白
You have no idea.
我喜欢卡马洛跑车
I love camaros.
-我现在没空  好吗  -别这么没种
- I can't do this right now, okay? - Don't be a wimp.
天哪
Oh, god.
-我第一辆车是我爸的92年版z-28  -是吗
- my first car was my dad's 92 z-28. - Yeah?
加满油以后
Fuel-injected.
引擎的咆哮声让我浑身兴奋
The roar of the engine, it just, tickles me.
我们还没发展到
We shouldn't, uh, share... I mean, share stories...
没发展到互诉心声的地步吧
To each other at all.
拜托  山姆  我只是搭个车
Come on, sam, just one ride...
歌名:Your Cheatin Heart<口是心非>
音乐:The Jaws Theme<大白鲨主题曲>
歌名:Super Freak<风骚浪女>
停下  停下
Don't. don't.
收音机坏了吗
Is your radio broke?
-不  我脑子坏了  -我们没偷情
- No, my concentration is. - We're not cheating.
现在还没
Not yet.
这是怎么了
Something wrong here?
天哪  你没事吧
Ow! oh, god! you okay?
歌名:Brick House<性感尤物>
真不知道怎么告诉你
I really don't know what to tell you,
这车  有很多毛病
This car-- it just has a lot of problems.
很多毛
A lot of prob--
天哪  进我嘴里了
Oh, god. oh, it's in my mouth. oh...
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我有湿纸巾  我拿湿纸巾给你擦脸
I got wetnaps. I got wetnaps for your face.
等等
Hold on.
真对不起
I'm so sorry!
你想干吗
What are you doing?
一天都不让我安宁  是吧
You won't give me a day, huh?
-这可是我第一天入学  -对不起  山姆
- You won't give me one day in college. - I'm sorry, sam.
但火种源最后一块残片还是被偷了
But the last fragment of the all-spark was stolen.
怎么  是霸天虎干的吗
Like what? like decepticon-stolen?
我们应政府的要求将残片交给人类保管
We placed it under human protection at your government's request.
但我需要你的帮助  山姆
But I'm here for your help, sam.
因为你们的领袖认为  我们把仇恨带到了地球
Because your leaders believed we brought vengeance upon your planet.
他们或许是对的
Perhaps, they are right.
因此必须有个双方都信任的人
That is why they must be reminded by another human
来不断提醒他们
Of the trust we share.
-这与我无关  -目前是
- This isn't my war. - not yet.
但很快就有关了
But I fear it soon will be.
地球一定不能像塞伯坦星球那样
Your world must not share the same fate as cybertron.
所有种族都失去家园
Whole generations lost.
我知道  我  我也想帮你  真的
I know and I-I want to help you. I do.
可我不是你们驻地球的大使
But I'm not some alien ambassador.
我只是个有着寻常烦恼的普通孩子
You know, I'm a normal kid with normal problems.
做我该做的事
I am where I'm supposed to be.
对不起  我
I'm sorry, I--
真的对不起
I really am.
山姆  我们的大多选择不是由于命运的召唤
Sam, fate rarely calls upon us at a moment of our choosing.
你是擎天柱  你不需要我
You're optimus prime. You don't need me.
我们比你认为的还需要
We do... more than you know.
北大西洋 早上7时13分
美国特贝卡号核潜艇 SSN-754
发现新目标  方位214  有可疑目标接近
New contact, bearing 214 and possible hostile
威震天沉入点
Confirmed for project beat six drop-point.
-什么情况  -有5个目标
- What you got? - sue, pull five contacts.
正迅速潜至水下5000英尺
5,000 feet. diving fast.
情况不对  他们下潜的很快很深
There's something. They dive that deep, that fast.
-各就各位  -传令  各就各位
- Man battle stations. - Sealer one, man battle stations.
转舵朝向三分之二
Hell, now pull the rudder or head two-thirds.
下潜
Dive, cookie.
防守威震天的部队发现敌情  长官
The nest protecting nbe-1 are screening, sir.
那里是水下9300英寻
That is 9,300 fathoms down.
-没有深潜救助艇赶到吗  -没有  长官
- And no confirmed dsrvs on sight? - None, sir.
各位  我们有麻烦了
Then, people, we've got a problem.
█
手术刀：霸天虎成员
在霸天虎军中担任医官
拆掉最小的那个
Kill such little one.
有碎片就有能量
Sea shard, make energon.
█
威震天：霸天虎首领
外星战机、外星坦克 三变体
声纳搜索到6个目标  它们来势很快
Prime sonar now holds six contacts and they're coming up fast.
碰撞警告
Man collisional alarm...
距离500英尺
...are 500 feet.
快离开这儿
Let's get out of here.
天使六号
Angel six,
有六个敌人进犯
We got six hostiles coming down.
-即将发生碰撞  -距离100英尺
- collision imminent. portside-- - 100 feet.
准备防撞
Brace for impact.
红蜘蛛  我回来了
Starscream, I'm home.
威震天殿下  听说您复活
Behold, megatron, I was so relieved
我就放心了
To hear of your... resurrection.
你居然见死不救  你这可怜虫
You left me to die, you pathetic insect!
全是为了扩充新的队伍
Only to help spawn our new army,
让堕落金刚消耗了不少  而且你不在
The fallen decreased it, after all, in your absence,
总得有人来统领大局吧
Someone had to take command.
你
You...
太让我失望了
Are so disappointing.
即便我死了 也轮不到别人发号施令
Even in death, there's no command but mine.
我的主人  在地球上我辜负了你
My master, I failed you on earth.
火种源被摧毁了
The all-spark is destroyed,
没有它 我们的种族迟早灭亡
And without it, our race will perish.
你还有很多要学  徒弟
You have much to learn, my disciple.
方块只不过是个容器
The cube is merely a vessel.
它的能量和真谛不可能被摧毁
It's power, it's knowledge can never be destroyed.
只不过变换了形态
It can only transform.
-怎么可能  -方块的能量已经
- How is that possible? - It has been absorbed
被那男孩吸收了
By the human child.
拯救我们种族的关键就在他的大脑里
The key to saving our race now lies within his mind.
那就让我把他的大脑生生给拿出来
Well then, let me strip the very flesh from his body.
你会的 我的徒弟
And you will, my apprentice.
千年来 我一直梦想回到
In time. for millenia, I have dreamed of my return
那该死的星球  在那我也被
To that wretched planet, where I too was once betrayed,
曾经情同手足的首领们背叛过
By the primes I call my brothers.
只有首领才能打败我
Only a prime can defeat me,
而且现在仅存一位
And now only one remains.
是擎天柱  他在保护那个男孩
Optimus. he protects the boy.
这男孩可以带我们找到他
Then the boy will lead us to him
-我们就能报仇了  -是的
- And revenge will be ours. - Yes.
那男孩跑不掉的  他一直在我们的监视下
The boy will not escape us. We have him in our sights.
不补充能量的话  这些新生儿就会死掉
Without more energon, hatchlings will keep dying.
空间  时间  地心引力
Space, time, gravity.
-谢谢  -帮我吃完吧
- Thank you. - Finish that for me.
今天我和你们要开始一段旅程
We're going on a journey together, you and I, today.
你们这些渴望成熟刚进入成年期的年轻人
All you, eager nubile young minds on the very cusp of adulthood.
我是你们的伙伴  是指路人
And I shall be your consort, your guide,
是监护人  带领你们进入黑暗的中心
Your chaperone, into the heart of darkness.
欢迎来上我的基础天文课
Welcome to astronomy 101.
我们对星星的了解有多少
For what do we know about the stars?
室女座  也就是处女座
Virgo... the virgin.
猎户座  也就是伟大的猎人
Orion, the great hunter.
可它们没有闪耀的钻石
These are no mere twinkling diamonds
供纯情少女们日思夜想
For lovely maidens to wish upon.
不  它们就是钻石  充满了
No, they are diamond, filled with a throbbing,
惊人的  随时要喷发的能量
Savage and hemped-up energy.
看看阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦的理论
Behold the work of Albert Einstein,
那位像我一样的教授的理论
A professor once, like moi,
-能量  在其质量等于  -你干吗
- Energy, in its mass temp-- - What are you doing?
把手放下  放下
Put your hand down, put your hand down.
年轻人  请在我讲到高潮后
Young man, there are no questions
再提问
Until I've reached the climax of my lecture.
我刚看完你的书  发现了一个问题
I've just finished your book. There's only one problem.
爱因斯坦错了
Einstein's wrong.
在这个维度里  能量不等于质量乘以光速的平方
Energy doesn't go mass times velocity light square in this dimension.
那其它十七维空间呢
What about the other 17
但我们无法给出十七维空间
While we're impossible to give 17?
例如
For example
各位  没人同意我说的吗
Come on, guys, I can't be the only one in class--
小伙子 你不能在系主任面前羞辱我
Young man, I will not be punked in front of the dean.
这里我说了算  明白吗
No, this is my universe here. Do you understand?
我就是一切
I am the alpha and the omega.
-立刻给我出去  -是  老师
- Get out of my class. - Yes, sir.
还有谁想要精神崩溃
Any one else care to have some sort of mental breakdown?
大骨头
Hi, bones. hi!
真是个乖孩子
Hi! oh yes, that's a good boy.
你今天真乖 太乖了
Oh, what a good boy, you are.
大骨头
Hey, bones.
饿吗
You hungry?
吃吧
Here you go.
-喂  塞缪尔  -喂  米凯拉
- Yes, samuel. - Hello? Mikaela.
我不敢相信  第一次视频约会你就放我鸽子
I can't believe you're gonna stand me up on our first web chat date.
我有麻烦了
Something just happened to me, okay?
-怎么  你终于进入青春期啦  -不是
- Wait, you finally hit puberty? - No, no, no,
别笑了  认真点
Stop laughing. this is serious.
记得我告诉过你
Okay, remember I was telling you about
我的曾曾祖父  阿基保尔·威特维奇
My great-great-grandfather, archibald witwicky?
记得吗
Do you remember?
看着点
Watch where you're supposed to go!
记得我告诉过你
Okay, remember I was telling you about, okay...
停下  别踩着  别踩着
Can you stop... watch the foot! watch your foot!
米凯拉  我说过我的曾曾祖父去过北极  对吧
Mikaela, okay, my great-great-grandfather went to this arctic mission, right?
他看到了威震天  威震天击中了他
And he saw megatron, megatron zapped him
然后他开始看到一些些古怪的符号
And he started seeing these crazy symbols, okay.
现在我也看到了  对不起
Well, now I'm seeing them too. excuse me.
我刚用32.6秒读完了903页天文课本
I just read a 903-page astronomy book at 32.6 seconds
在课堂上闯了祸
And had a meltdown in the middle of my class.
我看到符号了  自从我
I am seeing symbols ever since I--
-自从什么  -自从接触了方块碎片
- since what? - ever since I touched the cube sliver.
东西在吧
Do you have it?
是的  我放在店里的保险箱里了  很安全
Yeah, I have it in the shop safe? It's fine.
米凯拉  不要碰它  好吗  别碰它
Mi--mikaela, do not touch it, okay? don't touch it.
我不会碰它
I'm not gonna touch it,
山姆  它很安全  锁着呢  没人知道在哪
Sam, it's fine. it's locked away, no one knows where it is.
但我知道了
But I do.
你性感  但你很笨
You're hot, but you're ain't too bright.
开工了
There we go.
该死
Oh, big son of a bitch!
看什么看  流口水的傻姑娘
What are you looking at, slobber puss?
靠
Ah, what the--
这地方简直太可怕了
This is a fricking house of horrors.
等等
Hold on.
你就会用火钳夹是吧
Is that the best you got, huh?
就这么点能耐吗
Is that the best you can do?
你想干什么 你这小怪物
What are you doing here, you little freak?
我的眼睛  你这疯婆娘
Ow, that's my eye, you crazy bitch!
还不快交代
You gotta talk now?
堕落金刚叫我找方块里的真谛
I... I seek knowledge of the cube. The fallen demands me.
什么真谛
What knowledge?
你有碎片  我要碎片  给我碎片  我要碎片
You got the shot, I need the shot, give me the shot, I need the shot.
给我碎片  不然他们会劈了我
Give me the shot, they're gonna whack me,
拿不到碎片他们会杀了我
I'm gonna be dead without that shot.
放松  女战神  我只是个卖命的小苦力
Easy warrior goddess, I'm just a little salvage scrap drone.
那遇上我是你倒霉
Then I'm your worst nightmare.
-那是什么声音  -回头告诉你
- What the hell was that? - I'll tell you later,
电话里不方便说
Just not on open phone line, okay?
我现在就去机场  今天下午就能到了
I'm gonna get on a plane right now. I'll be there later this afternoon.
小心点  山姆
Just be careful, Sam.
海思在看着你
今天有没有陌生人让你带可疑物品
And have any stranger giving you anything suspicious to carry on today?
有  一大箱子
Yeah, a large box!
-没有  -很好
- No. - Good.
少校  博派发来求救信号
Major, incoming sos from autobots.
很多个霸天虎在行动
Multiple decepticon contacts in motion.
在美国东部附近  长官
Vicinity eastern united states, sir.
-汉兹文  有多少  -还不清楚  长官
- hansvin, how many? - Unclear, sir.
快点弄清楚
Well, get clear.
博派出动了  他们分成两个小分队  长官
Autobots on the move. splitting them into two teams, sir.
它们不回应呼叫  在向纽约和费城开进
Unanswer our calls, somewhere heading to new york and philadelphia.
全副武装  二十分钟后起飞
Full weapons deployment. wheels up in 20 minutes!
57次航班  欢迎来到费城
Flight 57, welcome to Philadelphia.
爱丽丝  亲爱的  来份超大比萨怎么样?
M'amor , can I interest you in mayteam zookeeper's special?
奶酪加大三倍 每种肉都有
Extra large supertees with every known animal as a topping.
这肉饼直径有18英吋
Basic lengths of 18 inches and just meat.
你是素食者  好吧  太好了  我也是
Oh, so you're a vegetarian. alright, it's cool. I am too.
山姆在吗
Is sam home?
山姆  死了吧  我们看看去
Sam... I think he died but, why don't we check?
-到了  -嗨
- Here we are. - hey.
你们有过脑子里总是反覆放同一首歌
Have you had a song stuck in yours?
很难听  但你却忍不住
It's like the worst song ever, but you can't help
一直哼着  就像是  来回放
Whistle it or sing it. it's like, repeats itself,
来回放  来回放  来回放  来回放
Repeats itself, repeats itself, repeats itself, repeats itself,
来回放  猫咪日历  猫咪日历
Repeats itself... kitten calendar, kitten calendar,
-猫咪日历  猫咪日历  -老兄
- kitten calendar, kitten calendar, - dude,
-猫咪日历  猫咪日历  -怎么了
- kitten calendar, kitten calendar, - what the f?
我知道你要崩溃  别崩溃  别崩溃
I know you're freaking out. don't freak out, don't freak out.
很容易解决  我脑子里都是代码  我都写墙上了
Easy fix. puzzle, code, in my head. now it's on the walls.
一切都好
Everything is good.
这部分
This is the part that--
好的  刚才你说啥
Okay, what were you saying?
爱丽丝  对不起把你吓着了  我们走
Alice, I'm horrified you had to see this. let's go.
-出去  -什么
- Get out. - What?
等等  我能旁观吗
Wait, wait, wait. C-can I just sit and watch?
我不说话  我吃比萨
I-I'll eat my pizza quietly.
山姆  我知道你有非同常人之处
Sam, I knew there were something special about you.
真的吗
Really?
你我都清楚
And I know you know what happens
一男一女同处一室会发生什么
When two people in the room get together...
他们在床上让人无比...惊异
They're genuinely amazing... in bed.
-谢谢你  -不客气
- Thank you. - No problem.
好吧  等等  保持距离
Alright, listen, hold on. boundaries. flight on the plane.
我很怕痒
Okay, I'm very ticklish.
-你需要的  山姆  放松  -为什么
- You have the need, sam. relax! - why?
天哪
Oh, jeez!
聊聊经济吧  很疯狂  是吧
Uh, what about this economy? It's crazy, isn't it?
-你太主动了  -放松就好
- You are very aggressive. - Just relax.
想来点烘干肉卷吗
You want some jerky meatloaf?
山姆
Sam?
米凯拉
Mikaela.
你女朋友吗
Is that your girlfriend?
前女友
Ex.
米凯拉  等等  听我解释
Mikaela, wait... I can explain every...
█
爱丽丝：霸天虎成员
新型人形机器人
山姆  你的床友  爱丽丝
Sam, your bed-buddy, alice.
什么
What...
-来了  -是外星机器人
- It's coming! - This is an alien robot.
-快跑  -难道是真的
- You gotta move. Just run. - They're real?
天哪  难以置信  我做春梦还梦到她
Oh my god, I can't believe I once had sex with her in my dream.
你可真是想念我啊  山姆
I can tell that you really missed me a lot, sam.
这不是我的错  好吗
Look, it's not my fault, okay?
听着  我是受害者
Listen, listen. I'm a victim.
你是受害人  受什么害
Oh, you were a victim? Of what?
-受什么害  一个80磅的女孩  -是  是
- Of what? A little 80-pound girl... - Of--of...
就像被头野公牛给上了一样
It's like getting humped in the neck by a mountain ox.
你不该把舌头放她嘴里
You didn't have to put your tongue in her mouth.
-我没有  -你有
- I didn't. - You did.
你绝对不愿意让五只脚的野牛在你胃里搅和
You ever had your stomach tounged by a mountain ox with a 5-foot tong?
对我来说可不好玩  米凯拉
It's not fun for me, okay, Mikaela.
而且一股柴油味  满嘴都是
And it smelled like--like diesel. like a diesel he tinged to it.
你真弱智
You're such a little girl.
我们现在先安静十秒
You have ten seconds of silence, right now.
我不和你说了
I'm not talking to you for ten seconds.
你不能不理我  知道吗
No, you can't give me the silence. you know what?
我10秒钟不理你  还有3秒
I'm not talking to you for ten seconds. you have three seconds left.
你想不理我就不理我
You know what? you can give me the silence you want,
随你便  但是你不能不让我说
All you want but you can't give me the talking...
你想说什么
W-what were you gonna say?
我希望你玩的开心
I hope you had a lot of fun because this--
因为我们俩结束了
This is over!
她最后是不是让你就范了
Did she finally led you to orbits?
她把脏舌头伸到你嘴里了  真伸进去了
You threw a broom? she did it, she went in it?
你肚子会有小外星人的 你得马上吐出来
...gestating in that inside of you. you're going right now, bro.
马上吐出来  吐  快吐
You need to vomit right now. yak it, yak it.
-现在就吐  -你是谁
- right now! - who are you?
我是唯一能让他吐出来的人  好吗
I am the only one who everybody can spit, okay?
但我是关键人物
I'm the key to this.
外星人要抓我是因为我的网址
Aliens; they want me because of my site.
快跑
Run!
米凯拉
Mikaela!
小心点  我们进去
Watch out. we get in.
是炸弹
It's a bomb!
我们得拿那个盒子
We gotta get that box.
这边
This way.
放我出去  放我出去
Hey, let me out, let me out!
天啊  你知道用火线发动车?
Oh my god, you know to hot-wire a car?
-那可真棒  -开车  开车  快开啊
- that's so hot. - drive, drive, drive.
她在那  她在那
She went there, she went there!
等一下
W-wait!
他们能
They can....
快快快
Cut, cut, cut.
上帝啊
Oh god!
看这下子  臭女人
Kiss this, bitch.
开车  走  走  走
Drive, drive, drive, drive, drive, drive.
到底是怎么回事
Okay, so what else's going right now, alright,
你们是不是没告诉了细节
Did you guys just mess with the minor details?
你刚才看到的那只是小喽啰
Thing you saw back there. that was a little babe.
天啊  天啊
Whoa! oh my god! oh my god!
山姆
Sam!
-山姆  -抓住
- sam! - hold on!
抓住
Hold on.
山姆
Sam!
我不想死  我们要玩完了  我的天啊
I don't want to die! we're going to die! oh my god!
上帝啊
Oh, Jesus! oh, jeez!
过来  小子
Come here, boy.
再近点
Closer.
好的
Okay.
-还记得我吗  -你照你说的做  好吗
- you remember me, don't you? - I did what you said, okay?
-但不要伤害我们  -闭嘴
- just don't hurt us. - shut up!
山姆
Sam!
第一个逮住你感觉真好
It feels good to grab your first.
我要杀掉你  慢慢地  痛苦地
I am going to kill you, slowly, painfully.
但我们先来点精细活
But first, we have some delicate work to do.
我能将你的肋骨掰下来
I could snap your ribs off.
医生  检查这个外星物种
Doctor, examine this alien specimen.
先看看你的脸
Sick of your face now.
这边来
Go that way.
这些虫子很暴躁
A wormy that's crabby--
-就是这些  -那就是我脑海中浮现的
- oh, there they are. - that's what I'm seeing in my head.
那些符号能使我们找到能量之源
These symbols can lead us to the energon source.
我们把他脑子拆开看看
We must tear the brain!
大脑  关我大脑什么事
Brain? what does he mean by my brain?
你脑子里有东西
Well, you have something on your mind.
-我需要的东西  -等一下  我知道你生气了
- something I need. - hold on. I know you're pissed.
我知道你生气了
I know you're pissed.
因为我想杀了你  我完全理解
Because I tried to kill you and it's completely understandable.
要是有人要杀我  我也会很伤心
Somebody tried to kill me, I'd be upset too.
我想我们有个机会
I think that we have an opportunity here
重新开始建立我们之间的关系
To start a new and--and develop our relationship,
看看我们的发展会怎样  好吗
And--and, see where it leads us, okay?
所以你就让医生助手
So you just call doctor stop inspection,
让你和我说一会话
I'll let you talk in five seconds.
等一下
W-wait...
快跑  快
Go, go.
跑  跑  快跑
Go, go, go.
山姆
Sam!
快跑  快  快
Go, go, go, go!
他来了
Here he comes!
藏起来  山姆  藏起来
Hide, Sam! hide.
懦夫
Weak.
废物
Puny.
行尸走肉
Voiced-up.
废物一堆
Junkyard drone.
霸天虎
Decepticons!
█
冲浪板：霸天虎成员
西科斯基重型运输直升机
出来  小子
Come here, boy.
还有一个能量源隐藏在这个星球上
There is another source of energon hidden on this planet.
这孩子可以带我们找到它
The boy can lead us to it.
擎天柱
Optimus!
难道我们种族的未来还不如一个人类重要吗
Is the future of our race not worth a single human life?
擎天柱  站起来
Op, get up!
你不可能杀一个人就罢手
You'll never stop at one.
我不能放过你们
I'll take you all alive.
山姆  你在哪
Sam, where are you?
你不行了
You are so weak.
领袖终于死了
At last, prime is dead.
山姆  快跑
Sam, run.
博派  进攻
Autobots, attack!
大黄蜂  带他们走
Bumblebee, get them out of here.
我是论诺克斯
This is Lennox.
干得比不错
That went well.
主人  男孩丢了
Lost the boy, master.
肯定是博派把信号屏蔽了
The autobots must be shielding the signals.
-你真靠不住  -对不起  我没用
- I can't even rely on you. - sorry. no.
连个草履虫都搞不定
What a simple insect!
-但他是70亿草履虫之一  -闭嘴
- what insect amongst severed billion-- - shut up.
大海捞针啊
It could be anywhere.
那就逼着人类帮我找到他
Then we will force them to find him for us.
是时候让世人知道我们了
It's time for the world to know of our presence.
再不伪装  毫无仁慈
No more disguises, no mercy!
该轮到我主人出场了
Time has come for my master's arrival.
霸天虎  出发
Decepticons, mobilise.
时间到了
It is time.
单身真好
Oh, that single's good!
说法语很有意思
Speaking french is so exciting.
天啊  这又是谁
Oh god, who is this?
你好  我是说  你好(法语)
Hello-- I mean, uh, bon--bonswa !
什么  你是谁
What? who is this?
求求你了
Oh, for Pete's sakes.
你在电话里瞎喘什么
I'm not impressed with your perverted mouth breathing.
纽约市
天啊
Oh, Jeez.
你侵犯我私人空间  小心我揍扁你
You are invading my space. I'm gonna have to drop you.
赶快滚开
Would you get out of here?
求你了  赶紧把那什么动物的尾巴吃完
Come on. In your way just finish the nails.
我想吃点新菜
We're gonna try new things.
就像加拿大天鹅粪
Looks like candian goosepoop.
真恶心
It's nasty.
美国第二舰队  北大西洋
收到  方向125
That's fine, 1-2-5.
我要报仇
Revenge is mine.
五角大楼   华盛顿
港口事故可能是恐怖袭击或更糟糕的袭击
...port accident for a terrorist attack, or worse.
不是  防空司令部确定
Negative.NORAD confirmed
投放物来自大气层以外
Project came from beyond our atmosphere
时速高达三万节
Inbound at 30,000 knot.
地球上的人类
Citizens of the human hive,
你们的领导掩盖了事实
Your leaders have withheld the truth.
你们在这个宇宙中并不孤单
You are not alone in this universe.
我们就在你们当中
We have lived among you, hidden...
但再也不隐藏了
But no more.
你们都看到了
As you've seen,
我们能随意摧毁你们的城市
We can destroy your cities at will.
除非你们交出这个男孩
Unless you turn over this boy.
你们胆敢反抗
If you resist us,
我们必将摧毁整个世界
We will destroy the world, as you know it.
德国政府表示
What we're hearing from the German government is that
这段讲话通过非法入侵卫星得以播出
The world broadcast is a satellite hacking.
军方透漏
the military has just told us
基地部队 新泽西州
安全防御级别已升至三级
They have assumed condition delta,
是9·11事件以来使用的最高级别
Which is the highest level we've been at since 9/11.
总统奥巴马已飞抵美国中部的
President Obama is being flown to a bunker,
某地下掩体
Somewhere in the middle of the united states.
以应对此次全球同一时间
In the phase of the worst simultaneous attacks ever
遭受的袭击
Around the globe.
美国罗斯福号航空母舰在美国东海岸沉没
The aircraft carrier, USS roosevelt, goes down off the east coast
无一人生还
All hands lost.
世界范围内的伤亡人数大约在七千人左右
Worldwide casualties are in the neighbourhood of 7,000,
但数字仍在暴涨
But that number could implode.
尚无法确定
It's still too early to tell.
我们想知道  敌方是谁 为什么攻击
What we need to ask now, is who and why.
联邦调查局仍在寻找这个叫山姆·威特维奇男孩
The FBI is still trying to locate the boy, Sam Witwicky.
联邦调查局新闻发布会
他们应该知道整个袭击的内幕
Within deep, they have information about this.
联邦调查局 中情局 国际刑警组织
The FBI, CIA and interpol
都在寻求各国司法部门的相关协助
Are all seeking the cooperation of worldwide law enforcements.
哥们 听听这个
Hey bro, you need to listen to this, man.
-过来看看  -他们曾用交通摄像头
- you gotta check this out. - once they have a traffic camera
-拍到山姆·威特维奇  -他们有我的照片  哥们
- spotting a Sam Witwicky. - they have a picture of me, man.
我们完了  老兄  联邦调查局  中情局正在通缉我们
We're dead, bro. FBI, CIA, we're wanted fugitives now.
你能不能听我说一分钟
I just need you to focus just one minute, man.
现在整个事件已经升级  对吗
This thing is blowing to a whole another level, alright.
-听我说  -把他给我
- you know one thing-- - remove this thing.
他们可以追踪到我们  你知道吗?
They can track us. do you see this?
什么
What?
可以追踪到我们
They can track us?
就像卫星跟踪我们一样
Like satellite-track us?
我都不和你们是一伙的
I'm not even with you guys.
实际上我就是人质  这是绑架  够了
Technically, I'm like a hostage. this is kidnapping. enough--
你想要吓死我吗?
This thing's gonna give me a heart attack, I swear.
-因为你是胆小鬼  -是你逼我上你车的
- that's 'cause you was a wuss. - you did force me into the car, right?
-那又怎样  -我觉得你怕了
- so... - oh, I think you scared.
挡泥板
Hey, mudflap.
我们该怎么处理这个大虾玉米卷
What are we going to do with this shrimp taco?
干掉他  扔到车箱里
Just pop a cap in his ass, throw him in the trunk
没有人知道
And nobody gonna know nothing, y'know I mean?
-等等  你是说我的车厢?  -碰碰车
- wait, now my trunk-- - yo, bumper cars,
小心点  我听得见  好吗
Check it out. I'm hearing you, okay?
我正在这听你们说呢
I'm right here and I can hear you.
别再刺激我了  行不
No one's popping any caps in any asses, okay?
我已经很倒霉了
I've had a hell of a day.
你怎么不去找你的女人整个发型
Why don't you get a haircut with your bitch ass?
去和山姆理论吧
Go whine to your boyfriend.
听着山姆   我知道该做什么
Listen sam, I know what I'm gonna do, man.
我会告诉政府真相
Look, I'm just going to go to the authorities
我什么也没有参与
And tell them the truth. like I had nothing to do with this,
我只是从犯
I'm an accomplice.
是你自愿的  对吗  你想知道真相
You wanted this, right? you wanted the real deal?
这就是  醒醒吧  你已经脱不了干系
'cause that's what this is. wake up! you're in the middle of it.
想走你就走  没有人拦你
You wanna run, go ahead, no one's stopping you.
别再抱怨了
Stop complaining.
这是什么意思
What is the meaning of this?
你竟敢用枪指着我
You dare point your gun at me?
你敢动我跟汗毛  我就把你们撕碎
You want a piece of me? I will tear you apart!
放下武器  放下武器
Drop your weapons! drop your weapons!
-让他们放下武器  -让汽车人先放下
- tell them to lower the weapons. - tell them first.
-让他们放下武器  -少校  我无能为力
- tell them to lower the weapons! - major, there's nothing I can do.
和他谈谈
Talk to him.
美国军队解散  少校
US teams deactivated, major.
要停止一切对抗霸天虎的行动
You are decease anti-Decepticon operations,
返回迪戈加西亚待命
And return to Diego Garcia. any further orders?
我们只直接听从莫苏华将军的指令
No. we take our orders direct from chairman Morshower.
我参加参谋首长联席会见到你的将军
Well, I'll see your chairman and the joint chiefs of staff
但是我现在命令你听从总统的
But I will raise you a president of the united states.
我有总统手令
I have operational command now.
外星人的仇恨已经殃及我们
An alien blood feud has been brought to our shores
让我们的士兵付出代价
For which our soldiers are paying the price.
真相大白  这不关我们的事
The secret is out. this is our war now.
我们还要像往常一样  运用联合的军事战略
And we will win it as we always have,
赢得此战
With a coordinated military strategy.
这个蠢货完全被骗了
This fool is terribly misinformed.
你可以得到所有需要的支援
You're gonna get every assets that you've got.
我们需要的是制定战争策略
What we need is to draw our battle plans.
我们要想出任何可行的外交策略
What we explore every possible, diplomatic solution.
交出孩子吗
Handing over the kid?
任何可行的策略都要一试
All options are being considered.
无论霸天虎要干什么
Whatever the Decepticons are after,
这只是开始
This is just the start.
等等  决不能和他们谈判
Wait, there is no negotiating with them.
我命令你解除战备状态
I'm ordering you to stand down.
你不再需要这个了
You won't be needing this any more.
把你的部队带回基地
Get your assets back to base.
还有那堆废铜烂铁也带走
Take that scrap metal back to Diego Garcia.
我们走
Let's go.
这家伙真讨厌
I really don't like that dude.
真是个混蛋
He's a asshole.
博派  回车库进行转移
Autobots, report to hangar for transport.
铁皮  我们该离开这个星球
Ironhide, we should leave this planet.
擎天柱绝不想让我们离开
That's not what optimus would want.
你已经尽力了
There's nothing that you could have done.
-你还好吗  -还好
- you okay? - yeah.
大黄蜂  如果你恨我  我可以理解
Bee, if you hate me, I understand.
是我搞砸了
I messed up.
对不起
I'm sorry.
小伙子  你是我一生中最在意的人
young fella, you are...person I care about most in my life.
如果你需要  我不会离开
if there's anything you need...I won't be far away.
他是因为我死的
He's dead because of me.
他保护了我  自己却死了
He came in to protect me instead.
世界上有些事是无法改变的
There's some things you just can't change.
这次牺牲
So this sacrifice was...
不能白白算了  哈利路亚
Will not have been in vain, hallelujah!
我要亲自改正这错误
We make it right when we turn myself in.
但是我们要团结一致
But we, we've got to stick together.
你不会来真的吧
You're not gonna do that.
是的
Yes, I am.
我们以前一切的努力会在
Everything we worked for will be wiped out.
一天内全部消失
In one day.
-你们两个  -什么
- you two. - huh?
你知道这些象形文字吗
Hey, you know the glyphs?
在我大脑里浮现的标志
The symbols that have been rattling around in my head.
那是很老的字体
That's old school, yo.
像是塞博坦文
That's like-- that's Cybertonian.
那可是很高深的东西
Oh, that's some serious stuff in there.
这些应该代表什么  比如信息
They gotta mean something, like a message...
或者地图
Or, like a-- like a map!
通向能量之源的地图
Like a map to an energon source.
你能读懂吗
Can you read this?
-读懂  不行  -看见了吗
- read? nah. - you see that?
我们认的字太少了
No, we--we don't really do much reading.
-太少了  -如果你们不能读
- not so much. - well if you can't read it,
我们就要去找人解读
We gotta find somebody who can.
看看谁走了又回来了
Oh, look, who came stashing and back.
头发长得像土豆丝  瞧瞧
Hair grown like a chip, there, look it.
我之前只是有点小小的恐慌  好吗
I had a bit of a mild panic attack earlier, alright?
所以你就像个女人似的
That's 'cause you're a pussy.
想想我经历的事情  我的反应也可以理解
I think I'm allowed that considering what I've been through
而且我听说你们遇到麻烦
And... I heard you have a problem.
我知道有个人可以帮忙
I think I know someone who can help.
-谁  -机器战士
- who? - Robo-warrior.
林肯公园
Linkin park
这家伙  机器战士
This guy, Robo-warrior...
所有外星人的信息他都知道
Everything about anything alien, he's supposed to know.
以前我们黑过他的网站
One time we hacked this site
也许我看到过你那些外星人的标志
And maybe, I saw some of your, uh... alien drawings or whatever.
就是这里
This is it.
熟食店 很不错的掩护
Yep, deli. good front.
在这等着  我招呼你们再进去
Alright, wait here. I'll give you the go/no go, alright?
42号  东西都打包好了
Number 42, we got your... right here...
-下一位  -我说过鲑鱼先用盐水泡再烟熏
- Show me who's next?  -I told you the simon in the brine and then smoke it.
妈  你要折腾死我吗
Ma, you want me to cut my handle off or what?
你订了条垃圾一样的鱼
You order a terrible piece of fishing.
我就像个带刀的忍者
I'm like a ninja, with a blade.
滚出去
Get out of here!
山姆  规矩点
Hey, sam! watch your reach, huh?
按号排队  小伙子
Take a number, young man.
机器战士
Robo-warrior.
你认识吗
Know him?
压根没听过
I never heard of him.
你没听过真实世界网站
You never heard of therealeffingdeal.com?
你说的是那个大外行博客组织吧
You must be talking about that amateur blog operation
防火墙不堪一击
With gameboy level security.
机器战士
Robo-warrior.
就是他  就是他  他就是那个人
It's him. it's him! that's the guy right there.
就是他
That's him.
不会吧
No.
开什么国际玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
本店打烊了  所有人出去
Alright, meat store's closed. everybody out!
出去  都出去
Go, right now!
慢着  你认识他
Wait a minute, you know this guy?
-我们是老朋友了  -朋友
- we're old friends. - whoa, friend,
就因为你  第七区撤销
You are the case that shut down sector 7.
全员遣散
Got the tie-bash disbandment,
没安保许可  也没退休金  一无所有
No more security clearance, no retirement, no nothing.
就是因为你  和这个少年犯女友
All 'cause of you, and your little criminal girlfriend.
现在她可长大了
Look at her now, so mature.
蠢货  肉哪里去了
Moron, where's the wifresh?
别拿死猪碰我
Don't catch me with the big.
- 雅科夫  -干嘛
- yakov! - what?
再不滚年底分红就取消
You don't get christmas bonus just standing around.
你想买电视商城里的那口好牙吗
You want those new teeth you saw in skymall?
-做梦都想  -那就滚远点
- it's my dream. - help around.
-你和妈妈一起住  -不  妈妈和我一起住
- you live with your momma? - no, my momma lives with me,
差别可大了
It's a big difference.
电视上到处是你的照片  外星人
They got your face all over the news, alien boy.
-我知道  -威震天还活着吗
- yeah, I know. - and nbe-1, still kicking, huh?
怎么回事
How did that happen?
别回答  我不知道你耍什么把戏
Don't answer. I don't know what you're hiding,
我也不想知道
But I don't want anything to do with it
后会无期  你只当没见过我
So, goodbye, you never saw me.
我要给施密特送百吉饼
I got bagels to Schmidt.
给我5秒钟
Well, give me 5 seconds.
等等  我需要你帮忙
Look, hold on, I need your help.
你要我帮忙  真的
Really, you need my help?
我需要—
I need--
我快神智不清了  好吧
Look, I am slowly losing my mind, okay?
一个小型螃蟹似的机械人
I had a little crabbot, placed the device
给我的脑软组织深层植入设备
Deep into the soft tissues of my brain,
映射出一堆外星符号
And started projecting little alien symbols
活像放惊悚片
Like a whole freaking movie
撇开这不说  我还是个通缉犯
And on top of that, I'm a wanted fugitive.
你觉得这还不够受吗
So you think you got it rough?
你说他能映射你的脑内图像
You said it projected images of your brain?
对
Right.
去冷藏室  快
Meat locker, now!
-死猪  -真恶心
- dead pigs. - yuck.
我给你们看的  都是最高机密
What you're about to see is top secret.
千万别告诉我妈
Do not tell my mother.
死猪  猪流感
Dead pigs, swine flu.
-真够糟的  -现在你们知道了
- not good. - now you know.
下次你们吃肉的时候
Next time, you eat a goat or a pig.
想想下面的故事吧
There's a story behind this.
对  还有故事呢
Yeah, there's a story.
你相信有外星人存在吗
...you're saying you believe in aliens?
文件  文件
Okay, files, files.
我们要找符号
We're talking about symbols.
别碰  那有放射性的
Hey! still radioactive. hands off.
好了  傻小子
Okay, cube-brain.
是这些符号吗
Any of these look like the symbols you saw?
这是哪来的
Where did you get these?
我离职前查的
Before I got fired.
我在第七区苦哈哈地
I coached s-7's scrawny, drooly...
进行了75年的研究  得出一个不容置疑的结论
75 years of alien research which points an indubitable fact.
变形金刚们  很早以前就来过地球
The transformers; they've been here a long, long time.
我怎么知道
How do I know?
考古学家在全球找到这些
Archaeologists found these unexplained markings
难以解释的印记和古老的符号
And ancient runes all over the world.
中国  埃及  希腊
China, egypt, greece.
这是1932年的影像
Shot at 1932.
这是你看到的符号?
These the symbols you're seeing in your head?
-是的  -一模一样  对吗
- yeah. - same ones over here, right?
为什么不同地方会有相同的符号
So, tell me, how did they end up all drawing the same thing?
最高机密
因为是外星人画的
Aliens.
我认为  有外星人留下来了
And I think some of them stayed.
瞧瞧这个
Check this out.
黑刃计划
Project black knife.
伪装过的机器人
Robots, in disguise. hiding here.
一直都藏在这里
All along.
我们在全国各地检测出放射源
We detected radioactive signatures all across the country.
我跪求上级批准第七区进行调查
I pleaded on my knees with s-7 to investigate it
但他们说数据量不足挂齿
But they said the readings were infintesimal.
说我疯了
That I was obsessed!
说我  你相信吗
Me, can you imagine that?
威震天说还有一个能量源
Megatron said that there was another energon source here.
-在地球上  -就在地球上
- on earth? on another source? - on earth.
那么  我脑中这些符号就是
Okay, and that these symbols,
指向能量源的地图
The maps in my head would lead him there.
你告诉那些博派朋友了吗
Should you talk to your autobot friends?
没有  能量源是早前的
No, no, no, the source is before.
不管是什么能量  都诞生于他们之前
Whatever the energon source is, it predates them. it's before them.
-是古代的  -没错
- so it comes before that. - correct.
那么  报告...
Well then, report...
除非能问到一个霸天虎
Unless we can talk to a decepticon.
不然  也不知道详情
I mean, I'm not on speed terms or whatever...
其实  我有一只霸天虎
Actually, I am.
放我出去
Let me out!
-样子挺可怜的  -打开吧
- it could be a little bit sad. - open it.
我要找一帮霸天虎打扁你
I'm gonna so many decepticons on your butt!
老实点
Behave.
-这是什么  霸天虎  -没错
- what is it, a decepticon? - yeah.
-你驯服了它  -试图而已
- can you train him? - tried to.
我花费一生  寻找外星生物
I spent my whole adult life, coming a plan of aliens.
-你脾气真够坏的  -你却牵着它
- you're very furious-- - and you're carrying it around
像牵着吉娃娃遛狗一样
What are you supposed to make a little chihuahua.
想打架吗  你个卷毛头
Wanna throw it down, you pubic fro-head?
对不起  我弄瞎你的眼睛了
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry about your eye.
但如果你乖乖的
You know, but if you're a good boy,
我就不弄瞎另一只
Then I'm not gonna torch your other eye.
好吗  我不折磨你了
Okay? I'm not gonna torch it.
告诉我这些符号什么意思就行
Just tell me what these symbols are.
求你了
Please.
好吧
Okay.
这些是古代领袖的语言
Oh, I know that. that's the language of the primes.
我不懂  但这些家伙们...
I don't read it, but uh, these guys...
你怎么搞到这些照片的
Where the frick did you find photos of these guys?
-这些是领袖吗  对
- is this them? - yeah.
猎隼是古早的领袖之一
Sakers, pal. oldest of the old.
他们千年前就来到地球
Oh, they've been here for thousands of years,
寻找某物
Looking for something.
我不知道是什么  没人告诉我
I don't know what, nobody tells me nothing.
有人明白符号的含义
Oh, they'll translate those symbols for ya.
我知道去哪儿找他们
And I know where to find them.
告诉我们
Show us.
最近的地点是华盛顿
Closest one's in washington.
美国航空博物馆
Smithsonian air and space museum.
梦想的国度啊
Land of dreams in there.
我曾经一心想当宇航员
All I ever want to be was an astronaut.
-拿着  -那是什么啊
- hold those. - what is that?
什么
What?
我穿着壮胆
I wear them when I'm in the funk.
基杨姆这骗子也这么干  棒球队员都这么干
So does jeamby, cheater. it's a baseball thing.
好了  对表  上好厕所
Okay. once you synchronize, shop-mind and empty bladder
万一被抓  记得请律师  千万别把我供出去
You get caught, demand an attorney and don't ever say my name.
把药拿着
Here, take one of these pills.
藏舌头下面
Slip it under your tongue,
这是放在奥利奥饼干里的高能浓缩聚合体
It's a high-concentrate polymer they put in oreo cookies.
骗测谎仪屡试不爽
Fools the polygraph, everytime.
好了  开工
Okay, now let's get this show on the road.
不不  我不干
Whoa, no, listen. I can't do this.
我不是外星赏金猎人
I'm not some alien bounty hunter, alright?
警卫都有枪  我不干
'cause I'm not gonna do this. guards have guns,
-我不想死  -孩子  孩子  孩子
- I don't want to die. - kid, kid, kid, kid, kid, kid.
你敢打退堂鼓  我就要你死得好看
You compromise this mission, you are dead to me.
现在看着我的眼睛  加强信心
Now look into my eyes, and tighten up that spare tank.
博物馆已关闭
The museum is now closing.
老兄  厕所没纸
Papa, bad news, bro.
糟透了  你们还有吗
Ran out of toilet paper, you got any out here?
-求你们了  -先生  你先进去再说
- please tell me you-- - sir, I suggest you get in there.
我们要闭馆了
The museum is closed.
听着  我明白  但是你看到了  没纸不行
Listen man, I understand that, but as you can see, this is important.
搞定我就走人  好吧
Dumper-dumper. I gotta go, alright?
先生  别光着屁股到处跑
Sir, you are a grown naked man around showing...
-穿上裤子走人  -我哪儿都不去
- pull your pants up and exit-- - I'm not going anywhere.
拿到纸巾了吗
You got that paper, right, sir?
你真该羞耻
You should be embarassed.
这里是家庭式博物馆
This a family museum, sir.
发生什么事
What is going on here?
你知道小弟弟被电多少次之后
How many times can you get tased in the nuts?
就生不了孩子了
So you can not have kids, huh, you know.
你真是外行  大外行
You're an amateur man, a rank amateur.
我干掉5个警卫了  5个了
There's now five guards. five guards.
-带上东西就走人  -给我点时间
- you get this stuff and get out of here. - give me a second.
我要拿检测仪  好了
I gotta get the tracker, alright.
-规矩点  -我有幽闭恐惧症
- be good. - I'm claustrophobic.
跟着它  跟着它
Look, look. follow him, follow him.
它知道怎么走
He knows where he's going.
-它有线索  -什么
- he knows something. - what?
它有线索
He knows something!
-你也找到了  -对
- you got what I got? - yeah.
乌鸫号
Blackbird.
就是它了
There he is.
它是传奇人物  地位相当于董事长
This guy's a legend, like--like the chairman of the board.
嘿  菜鸟  放上碎片
Yo, freshman, put the shard.
等着看魔术吧
And watch the magic happen.
糟  它是霸天虎
Oh shit, it's a decepticon!
-霸天虎  -什么
- decepticon? - what is it?
快找掩护
Find the main tail!
█
天火：初期变形金刚
寻找能量源的探索队成员
这什么破地方
What sort of hideous mosalleem is this?
虾兵蟹将都给我滚出来
Semi pulls and days, show yourselves!
不然让你们死无葬身之地
Or suffer my infinite wrath!
等等  脊柱被称为基础组织
W-wait, old spinal called based organisms.
他妈的
Bugger!
看清我天火永恒的光辉
Behold the eternal glory of jetfire!
启动远程系统
Prepare for a distant systems' somewhere.
跟你说  这家伙还真不显老
I tell you, this guy did not age well.
-他不会伤害我们吧  -给我开门
- Didn't he either hurt us. - command these doors to open.
开火
Fire!
我说  开火
Oh, I said, fire!
真没用
Bollocks
我来打烂这些没用的...
Break that, these worthless--
等等
Wait a second.
屁股生锈  又痒又难过
Itching, wretching, rust in my arse.
博物馆的人要疯了
Oh, the museum's gonna be very angry.
要疯了  我们得抓住那架飞机
Very angry. we gotta catch that plane!
我身负重任
I'm on a mission.
-等等  等等  等等
- w-wait, wait! - wait, wait, wait.
你要干嘛
what do you want?
我们得谈谈
Look, we just want to talk!
我没时间说话  我有任务
I've no time to talk, I'm on a mission!
我是残酷的雇佣兵
I'm a mercenary goon-bringer.
-这是什么星球  -地球
- what planet am I on? - earth.
地球  什么垃圾名字
Earth? terrible name for a planet,
干脆叫"土球"算了
Might as well call it "dirt".
满星球的土
Planet dirt.
告诉我  机器人内战还打吗
Tell me, is that robot civil war still going on?
-哪边赢了  -霸天虎
- who's winning? - the decepticons.
我换阵营到博派了
Well, I changed sides to the autobots.
"换阵营"  什么意思
What do you mean, "changed sides"?
这是种选择
It's a choice.
这完全是个人决定  那边太消极
It's intensely personal decision. so much negativity.
谁想一辈子活在仇恨里啊
Who wants to live a life filled with hate?
你不再给那些
Meaning you don't have to work for those
悲惨的  古怪的霸天虎干了
Miserable, freaking decepticons?
如果他们一直那样  宇宙会被毁灭的
If they set on their way, they destroy the whole universe.
我要换阵营  我要换阵营  女战神
I'm changing sides, I'm changing sides, warrior goddess!
-我是你的小汽车人  -你真可爱
- who's your little autobot? - oh you cutes.
叫我小车轮
Name's wheelie.
叫我吧  叫我吧
Say my name, say my name!
你就任它在你腿上乱来
What are you allowing to happen to your foot just now?
至少它专一  山姆
At least he's faithful, sam.
是啊  它不但专一  还够不要脸的
Yeah, well, he's faithful, and he's nude and he's perverted.
你能停下来不
Can you just-- can you stop?
-你干什么  -我不想说这个
- hey, what are you doing? - ...i don't wanna argue it.
你刚才说什么
What were you saying?
我说我的名字叫天火  别总惹我
I told you my name was jetfire! Stop charging me.
有人早上起来就不爽
Wow, someone shit in the bed this morning?
我很暴躁但是我妈遗传的
I am ambitious my own but it is from my mother.
我的先祖数千年前来到这里
My ancestors have been here for centuries.
我的父亲  有着第一个轮子  第一个轮子啊
My father, one was a wheel! the first wheel!
-知道他变形成什么吗 -不知道
- do you know what he transformed into? - no.
什么都变不了 但是他死得光荣 死得其所
Nothing! but he did so with honor, dignity and--
该死 我的助推器坏了
My boosters are fried.
我们应该互相帮助
I thought we could help each other.
你知道我不知道的  我知道你不知道的
You know things I don't know. I know things you don't know.
- 真的 - 我觉得他什么都不知道
- I do. - I don't think he knows anything.
老实讲我不知道
Honestly, I don't know.
这些鲜明的符号
These vivid symbols,
虽说是符号  但已深刻在我脑海
They're symbols but they are in my mind.
我脑子里就这些
You see, all this is in my mind.
威震天就是想要这些符号
And megatron wants what's in my mind.
他们叫他堕落金刚
Him and someone called the fallen.
堕落金刚  我知道那家伙
The fallen? I know him.
是他让我在这儿生锈
He left me here to rust.
霸天虎的创始者
The original decepticon.
那个霸天虎不好共事
He's terrible to work for.
满脑子都是毁灭  混乱  危机
he's always apocalypse, chaos...
这些符号也是我任务的一部分
His suspects, they were a part of my mission
堕落金刚要找 想起来了
The fallen search, I remember now.
要找匕首之尖和一把钥匙
Of a dagger's tip and the key!
等等  慢点  什么匕首之尖  钥匙
Slow down. the dagger's tip, the key,
-到底是什么  -没时间解释了
- what are you talking about? - no time to explain.
大家都抓紧了
Hold on, everybody!
天火具有初期变形金刚特有的天空桥技术
情况还没那么糟
Well, that wasn't so bad.
这次还在地球上
I was overseeing the wrong planet.
疼死我了
Hey, that frickin' hurt!
天哪
Oh, my god!
我的天
Oh, god!
天哪  你真漂亮  真是个完美时刻
Oh, my god! you beautiful face, this will be a perfect moment.
不过你砸在我蛋蛋上了
Except you landed on my testicles.
快起来
Please get off!
我的蛋蛋啊
My balls!
山姆
Sam!
这是哪儿  西蒙斯
Where are we? simmons!
我的天哪
Oh, my god.
这是哪儿  拉斯维加斯
What is this? it's vegas!
-都还好吗  -还好
- you guys okay? - yeah!
我想是到拉斯维加斯了
Hey! I think we're in vegas!
真是疼啊
That really, really hurts.
你很走运  我没伤着
You're just lucky that I didn't get hurt.
我要是受伤了  会死人的
People could've gotten killed, okay? and if I would have gotten hurt,
-你应该听说过  -闭嘴
- you would have heard from-- - oh, shut up!
我说了要架个时空桥梁
I told you I was opening the space bridge.
这样到埃及最快
It's the fastest way to travel to egypt.
你说什么啦  你什么都没说
What did you tell us? you didn't tell us anything!
你什么都没说  我们为啥来埃及
You didn't tell us anything. why are we in egypt?
别插话  乳臭未干的小子
Don't you dare slip in with me, fleshwing.
-我告过诉你了  -能停一下吗
- you would do the informed. - can you just stop for a second?
别跑题  能告诉我为什么来埃及吗
Can you focus? can you tell us why we're in egypt
我们才都有点心理准备
So we can all have a little bit assemblance and peace of mind?
我们种族以前就来过这个星球
This planet was visited by our race once before
第一代祖先百万年前就来过
By our earliest ancestors a millenium ago.
他们的使命是收集能量块
They were on an exploratory mission to harvest energon,
我们种族的生命之源
The life blood of our race.
没有它我们会腐烂氧化生锈
Without it, we'll all perish, oxidize and rust,
看看我这样子多可怜
Let my wretched self.
你们不知道慢慢腐朽而死的滋味
Do you have any idea what is like a slowly fall of parton die?
您别总跑题行吗  老先生
Let's not get episodic, okay? old-timer.
从头到尾简要把事实和结果说清楚
Beginning, middle, end. facts, details, condense, plot, tell it.
我们的祖先在沙漠的某一处地方
Somewhere buried in this desert,
建了个巨型机器
our ancestors built a great machine.
通过摧毁恒星来获得能量块
It harvests energon by destroying suns.
-摧毁恒星  -你是说把它们都炸掉
- destroy suns? - you mean blow them up?
对  最开始  曾经有七位领袖
Yes. you see, in the beginning, there were seven primes,
我们的第一批领袖
Our original leaders.
他们进入宇宙寻找遥远的恒星去采集能量
And they set out in the universe seeking distant suns to harvest.
领袖们规定
The primes set out
不能摧毁有生命的行星
Never destroy a planet with life.
后来其中的一位违背了这条规则
Until one of them tried to defy this rule.
他的名字就叫  堕落金刚
And his name, for ever more, was the fallen.
他不顾人类死活
He despised the human race.
他想启动那个机器来消灭人类
And he wanted to kill you all by turning on that machine.
而唯一能激活它的  就是传说中的钥匙
The only way to activate it is with a legendary key
也就是我们所说的领导之源
Called the matrix of leadership.
为了抢能量源发生了一场大战
A great battle took place over possession of the matrix.
堕落金刚比其他超级领袖更强大
The fallen who was stronger at his will did,
其他超级领袖只能偷出原能矩阵藏起来
Surrendered no choice, but to steal and hide it from him.
他们做了最后的牺牲
In the ultimate sacrifice,
以生命为代价将能量源封藏
they gave their lives to seal the matrix away
藏于用他们遗体铸成的坟墓里
In a tomb made of their very own bodies.
这座墓没有人知道
A tomb we cannot find.
在这儿  就在这沙漠某处
Somewhere, buried in this desert,
那座死亡机器还在
That deadly machine remains.
堕落金刚知道位置
The fallen knows where it is.
如果他找到了领袖们的墓
And if he finds the tomb of the primes,
你们的世界将不复存在
your world will be no more.
那我们怎么阻止他
Okay so how do we stop it?
只有领袖能打败堕落金刚
Only a prime can defeat the fallen.
比如擎天柱
Optimus prime?
你遇到过领袖吗
So you met a prime?
你遇到的肯定是个很强大的后代
You must have met a great descendant.
他还活着
Is he alive?
在这  这个星球上吗
Here? on this planet?
他为了救我而牺牲了自己
He sacrificed himself to save me.
那么他死了
So he's dead.
没有领袖就不可能了
Without a prime, it's impossible.
没人能阻止堕落金刚
No one else could stop the fallen.
如果这种能量能重启那台机器
So the same energy that's going to be used to reactivate the machine...
那它就能重启擎天柱
Could that energy somehow be used to reactivate optimus
让他死而复生吗
And bring him back to life?
能量源不是为这个设计的
It was never designed for that purpose,
但是这种能量非比寻常
But it's an energy, like no other.
在霸天虎抓到我之前
So then how do you get us to the matrix
您怎么带我们找到能量源
before the decepticons get to me?
用你的脑子里的地图  符号
Follow your mind, your map, your symbols,
你在沙地上写的就是线索
What you got in the sand, it's your bloom.
当曙光照耀在匕首之尖
When dawn alights the dagger's tip,
三位国王将打开入口
Three kings will reveal the doorway.
找到那入口
Find the doorway!
快去
Go now, go!
这是我的使命  现在也是你的使命了
That was my mission. it's your mission now.
要在霸天虎找到你我之前
Go before the decepticons find me
先找到入口
And find you.
中情局有线人说
That was my cia contact.
原始闪族人称亚喀巴海湾为
Says ancient sumerian used to call the gulf of aqaba
-匕首之尖  -匕首之尖
- the dagger's tip. - that's the dagger's tip.
-是红海的一部分  -我明白了
- it's part of the red sea. - got it.
就像刀刃一样  将埃及和约旦分开
It divides egypt and jordan like the tip of a blade.
北纬29.5度  东经35度
29 and a half degrees north. 35 east.
就是这儿
There it is.
首先得把擎天柱给弄过来
Okay, first thing we gotta do is get optimus to dagger's tip.
你怎么把他从地球对面弄过来
How are you gonna get him halfway around the world?
我们要打个电话
We're gonna make a call.
有警察追过来
We got the cops.
我不想进监狱  哥们
I can't go to prison, guys!
山姆  你得离开这条路  避一避
Sam, you gotta get off this road and lay low.
这帮白痴警察
Man, they'll picked cops.
这就是忍者的伪装术
This is just called blending in like a ninja.
我要尿在你脸上了
How about I'll lay my piss in your face?
他们走了
They're gone.
没时间了
Wait another time.
我要去打电话给论诺克斯
I got to make the call to lennox
你知不知道
You and the worldwide.
他们可以追踪全世界任意一个基站
what, they're gonna trackling in one base?
然后马上就可以追踪到你
They'll track you here in seconds.
遍地都是中情局的人
Cia is all over this place.
那你来打
You're gonna call?
好主意  主意不错
Okay, that's--that's a good idea.
-行吗  -我就是
- alright? - I mean I just was...
想起了别的
My mind in other things.
-比如  -比如你干吗没被抓住
-Like - why don't you get being chipped in prison.
新泽西州
基地部队  21点启程
2100 hours.
那么我们要返回基地了
So we're shipped in back to base.
这是个致命错误
This is central at stake.
伦诺克斯少校  电话
Major lennox, phone call.
伦诺克斯  我和那孩子在一起  那孩子  明白吗
Lennox, I'm with the kid. the kid, you know?
特有个性那个  知道吧
One with the attitude, right?
我需要卡车  卡车
I need the truck. the truck.
在这儿  我们可能让它重新工作
We got a possible resurrection going on over here.
你想不到我们在哪儿
You're not gonna believe where we are.
暗语  小孩找到了图坦卡门法老
Code tot has an king tutankhamen,
一美元钞票上背面上那位
Back of a $1 bill.
空降坐标如下  北纬29.5度  东经34.88度
Coordinates for air-drop, 29.5 north, 34.88 east.
听到了吗  写下来  写下啦
Get it. write it down, write it.
我的天哪
Oh, my god.
我得走了  我恨警察
I gotta go, okay. I hate the cops.
等等  你是谁
W-wait, who are you?
是我  里奥  里奥
Wait, it's me. leo, me, leo, leo. leo.
警察来了  快走  快  我们走
The cops are coming right now. we need to go.
坐标  北纬29.5度 东经34.88度
Coordinates 29.5 north, 34.88 east.
红海之端  亚喀巴海湾
Tip of the red sea, gulf of aqaba.
是埃及
Egypt.
你真要这么干
Are you serious?
长官
Sir.
即使我们真能这大家伙运到那儿
Even if we could figure out a way to get big man over there.
那孩子又怎么救活他
How is this little kid's supposed to bring him back to life?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我们得相信他
But we gotta trust him.
好  我们再想一遍
Okay, let's go over it again.
当曙光照耀在匕首之尖
when the dawn arise the dagger's tip,
三位国王  -将打开入口
- the three kings... - ...will reveal the doorway.
这是他原话  知道意思吗
That's what he said. you know what that means?
-不知道  什么意思  -我也不清楚
- no, what does it mean? - I have no idea.
糟了  检查站
Oh my god, oh my god. checkpoint, checkpoint.
我没带护照
I don't have my passport.
护照  快点拿出护照来
Passport. idiota !
上面有摄像头
They have cams at top.
他就是他们要找的那个人
He's the one that they want.
好了  放松  态度好点
Alright, chill. let's be nice to them.
我能搞定  这都是我的族人
I can handle it. these are my people.
我有三十六分之一的阿拉伯血统
I'm 1/36.
真好  一个矮冬瓜
Oh great, a frickin' munchkin.
小个子都自卑  告诉他  他很高
Oh, little people are mean. tell him he's tall.
-你要干什么  -我要去...
- what do you want? - I want to go to...
匕首之尖对吧
The dagger's tip, right?
埃及  约旦  我们想去那儿
Egypt, jordan. we wanna go there.
和家人一起  这是我们全家
Me and my family. this is my family.
-这是我儿子  另一个儿子  -你好
- this is my son, my other son. - hi there.
女儿
My daughter.
我们是来旅游的  从纽约来
We're tourists from new york.
-纽约  -对
- new york? - yes. yes.
五十公里就到
50 kilometres.
我们要尝尝你们特色菜  谢谢
We're going to get one of your falafels, thank you!
非常感谢
Yeah, thank you very much.
-纽约  -我们在哪儿见过吧
- new york. - I know, I know you from somewhere.
不  我们不是中情局的
No, we do not work for the cia.
所有霸天虎  男孩的位置
Decepticons, voice location.
已经探明
Detected.
红蜘蛛  已经出发
你得把自己伪装起来
Undercover, yo, you gotta blend in with your surrounding.
和周围融为一体
You know, you gotta be part of the landscape.
真壮观
Awesome.
应该是外星人建的
I think aliens built that.
对  对
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
来  进去
Go, move it! move it.
-什么  -给我们放风
- what? - hey, guard us.
安静点  别一惊一乍的
Low-profile, don't make a scene, okay?
有活儿要干啦
Yeah, some of us got work to do!
笨蛋汽车人
Dumb autobots.
基地部队  预计早上6点到达
做我女朋友其实挺危险
Being my girlfriend is hazardous to your health.
没错  女孩就喜欢爱冒险的男生
Yeah, well, girls like dangerous boys.
-真的  -对
- really? - yeah.
你还是说出来吧
Why don't you say it?
女士优先
Ladies first.
你今晚很绅士
Okay, so tonight, you're gonna be a gentleman.
倒挺有风度的
You're really chivalrous.
当时那么生气
Why are you mad at me?
你知道吗  宝贝
You know what? baby, I'm not...
我没有生气
I'm not mad.
我飞了三千公里就是不想看到你死
You realise that I just flew 3,000 miles to keep you from getting killed.
我知道
I know.
谁还能当你女朋友
Who else could be your girlfriend too?
看看我所经历的一切
Look at the things that go through with me.
现在在这美丽的月光下
And now we're underneath the moon and the stars
旁边还有地球上三个最漂亮的金字塔
And the three most beautiful pyramids on the planet
你还是不肯说出你爱我
And you still can't even tell me that you love me.
-怎么啦  -等等
- what? - wait.
-男人怎么总转移话题  -月亮和星星
- why do boys always change the subject? - the moon and the stars...
-山姆  我  -跟我来 快
- sam... - come with me really quick.
西蒙斯  里奥  快醒醒
Simmons, leo, wake up!
天文学课本第47页你还记得吗
Listen, astronomy class, page 47, you remember the class?
不记得  我只上了两天大学而已  你记得吗
No, no, I was only in college for two days, you remember that?
-起来 过来  -你说什么呢
- yeah, well, get up. up, up. - what are you talking about?
看见那三颗星星了吗
Can you see those three stars?
最下面一颗贴着地平线
You see how the last one touches the horizon?
那是猎户座
That's orion's belt.
也叫做三王星
It's also called the three kings and the reason for that is
得名于三位埃及国王
The three egyptian kings
专门在吉萨建造了金字塔
who built the pyramids in giza built them
来对应那三颗星星
To mirror those stars.
它们像条箭头一样摆在我们面前
So it's like an arrow staring straight in the face.
他们指向东方的约旦
They all point due east towards jordan.
指向佩特拉的群山
The mountains of petra.
引擎发生故障  我们必须减轻负重
We got a seatbelt malfunction. we gotta have to divert...
低空飞行  准备跳伞
Flight in lower, prepare for bail-out.
跳伞  要跳伞
Bail-out, bail-out, bail-out, bail-out?
好吧  所有人  背好降落伞
Alright, team, grab your shoots.
跳伞
Bail-out?
用过军用降落伞吗
Familiar with the standard mc-4?
当然没有  我以前没跳过民航飞机
Of course not. I've never jumped out of a publicly good airplane Before.
等等  这是真的吗
Wait a minute, is this really happening?
且慢且慢
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
你不是捉弄我吧
You're behind this, aren't you?
说什么呢
What are you talking about?
机长不是刚说完吗  那帮家伙是不会乱讲的
You heard the pilot. These guys don't mess around.
这是工作流程  我只是奉命行事
This is standard procedure. I'm just following orders to the letter.
这话不是你说的吗
Do you know what you said?
你真是不想混了
You, just send final order to  your career--
咋了  咋了
Wait, what was that? What's that?
情况不妙
That's not good.
来  跟我来这边
Come on. Right this way, right this way!
我不敢从飞机上跳下去
I can't jump out of an airplane.
这边来  来啊
Come here. Come here.
首先我要确保重要人物的安全
Because I have to secure the vips first.
现在  我希望您非常仔细地听
Okay, I want you to listen very carefully.
一定要记清楚我讲的每句话
Remember as everything that I say.
GPS设备必须朝东  你会被搜救
East to the gps trackers, so you can be found by search and rescue.
-听明白了吗  -听不清
- Look, are you listening? - I can't.
-好吧好吧  -行了
- Alright, alright. - Alright.
起跳时会遇到机身产生的气流冲击
When the plane that shoot inflates into the air,
这时要拉气栓放些气
Pull the pin and open some air,
排完气  拉主伞
Break your rack up, lose your primary.
就这蓝柄
I want you to pull the blue.
可要使点儿劲拉
I need you to pull it really hard.
别现在拉  现在还没起跳呢  白痴
Not right now. We're on the plane, you dumbass!
他说再见了吗
Did he say goodbye?
没有  没来得及
No, he didn't even say goodbye.
将军  已准备就绪
General, we're loaded and ready.
您一下令  五分钟后开始行动
You give us the go, and we'll be ready to press in five minutes.
-漂亮  -长官
- Excellent. - Sir,
您看下这个
You need to see this. Now.
伦诺克斯少校:
北纬29.5°  东经35.88°
十万火急
查出坐标位置了吗
Have we checked these coordinates?
埃及  他们在那里空降
Egypt, sir. They're air-dropping in.
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
他肯定有理由
He knows something.
我们必须支援他  以防事态升级
We need to be ready to back him up, if this thing goes hot.
收到
Copy that.
距伦诺克空降点一百公里
CIA just got a hit on the boy.
中情局得到那男孩的线报
Hundred miles from the location on that little map there.
越来越棘手了
It's getting hotter.
应该就在这儿...附近
It's gotta be... Around here somewhere.
就这儿附近  大伙
It's here somewhere, guys.
何以见得
Oh yeah, why?
我们只能相信黑鸟爷爷
'Cause we're trusting grandpa Blackbird
尽管他都不知道自己在哪儿
Who doesn't even know what planet he's on.
话说回来  这是我这辈子
On his defense, this is the biggest doorway
见到的最大的入口
I've ever seen in my entire life.
好的  咱们先摸摸底吧
Okay. Well, that's great. Let me do a quick search, alright?
啥都没
Nope.
似乎考古学家来过这儿了
Ever questioned mind, guys, that archaeologists have been here Before.
什么都没有
There's nothing here.
生活免不了痛苦和绝望  孩子
You realise it's heart-break, despair, kid.
马上就要成功了
Sometimes, you get to the end of the rainbow
老天还是会捉弄你一下
And the leprechauns went and booby-trapped it.
好意思说我  你连你妈都离不开
I'm listening to you; you live with your mother.
-还没结束  -结束了  完了
- It's not over. - It is over. It's done.
我们为啥还听你这个小屁孩的
Why are we still listening to your little punk-ass?
哪个傻瓜赞成我的主意
I mean, what kind of dumbfucks accept ding my rim?
杀了威震天  咋样
Kill megatron. How about that?
他没完成心愿  所以要回来
Well, he doesn't get the job done, you know, I mean,
-因为之前他被打败了  -你怕了吗
- 'cause he's zapped, man. - You scared?
怕吗  我就怕你那张丑脸
Well, scared? Scared of your ugly face.
说我丑  咱俩是双胞胎  蠢材
I'm ugly? Well, we twins, you stupid genius.
-尝尝我的厉害  -没打着
-...tense your face - You don't really get it!
兄弟们
Guys! Oh, hey!
滋味好受吗
You like the way that feels?
-一点不疼  -不敢了吧
- That ain't hurt. - You got that, don't you?
我要起来
I'm getting up
太粗鲁了
Now that's rude.
天  符号
Oh, my god! The symbols.
大黄蜂  轰开这里
Bee! Shoot it.
这就是老天火说的地方
This is the part what jetfire mentioned
领袖之墓
The tomb of the primes.
能量源
The matrix.
历经千年  灰飞烟灭
Thousands of years turned to dust.
结果不该是这样
This isn't how it's supposed to end.
听到了吗
Hear that?
美国空军C-17
Us air force. C-17s.
擎天柱救不活了  山姆  什么都没了
You can't bring it back, Sam, there's nothing left.
看看周围
Look, look around you.
世间万物因果相关
We didn't just go through everything we went through for no reason At all.
这还不能算结束
They just haven't end like this.
我们到这里必有因
There is a reason that we're here.
我脑袋里的符号和声音把大家领到这儿
The voices and the symbols in my head led us here...
只为一个目的
For a purpose.
所有人都因为我知道的事情追捕我
Everyone's after me because of what I know.
而我所知道的是  这肯定有用
And what I know, is that this is going to work.
你怎么知道这有用
How do you know it's going to work?
因为我相信
Because I believe it.
最好赶快让我下飞机
Best put me out of this plane.
放大家伙了  山姆
He's dropping the big one. Sam!
你不是真认为那堆土能救活他吧
You think you can bring him back to life with that pixie dust?
肯定能  走吧
Absolutely. Let's go!
走
Go!
快
Move it!
记住不扰平民
Remember your friendly!
把擎天柱隐蔽起来
Cover Optimus!
全村警戒  把弹药放到这来
Secure the village. Get those cases down here.
部署狙击手  安置导弹
Get snipers and stingers up high.
把这十吨重的机器人
So he just dropped off ten tonnes of dead robot
运到这不毛之地
In the middle of nowhere.
但愿这孩子心里有数
Hope this little kid know what he's doing.
我也这么想
Yeah, me too.
发现大黄蜂  四公里外
Got a visual! Yellow tee, four klicks.
发信号弹
Hot-flare!
他们在那儿  看到信号了吗
That's them right there. You see the flare?
就在那儿  看到没
Right over there! See it?
已找到男孩
山姆
Sam!
神啊  救我
Oh god, please god,
-拜托  -里奥  别叽歪了
- Please! - Leo, stop freaking out.
-闭嘴  -把这小子扔下车吧
- Just stop freaking out! - Just drop this guy off, huh?
-救我  让我活着  别让我死  -闭嘴
- Please let me live, just let me live. - Stop freaking out!
让他别叫唤就好了
Just stop screaming right now. That's it.
受不了这家伙
Can't take that guy anymore.
分头行动
We gotta split up.
大黄蜂  你上去引开霸天虎  好吗
Bumblebee, you are the decoy. You lead the decepticons away, Alright?
我去救擎天柱
I'm gonna get Optimus.
我帮忙吸引火力
I'll help throw their fire away.
你们去找大兵
You get to those soldiers.
真希望那堆土能管用  孩子
I hope that dust works, kid.
谢谢
Thank you.
他转回来了
It's turning around.
他回来了  他回来了
It's coming back, it's coming back.
交给我了
It's up to me.
孤胆英雄  精忠报国却不受重用
One man, alone, betrayed by the country he loves,
危难时刻却成为最后的希望
Now its last hope in the final hour of need.
待一代宗师驾驭你吧
The pants are to be driven like never before.
大师风范
Under my skin.
哪儿也别去  别走
Hey, hey, hey! Don't go nowhere.
-开车  -你干不了这个  孩子
- Drive! - You will never make it, kid.
光有勇气是不够的
Bravery will only get you so far.
你电晕过我  对吗  你欠我的
You tased me, okay? You owe me.
-我要去  -好的
- I'm go. - Okay, okay.
那是考验你的  你过关了  成了吧
That was a test. You passed, alright?
那家伙带着霸天虎的标志
Thing's got alien tattoos all over.
不是空军
That ain't air force.
怎么回事
What the hell was that?
-收到  -有人收到吗
- Eddy-1, copy. - Anyone there?
是谁
Who's up?
-收到  -通信中断
- Copy. - Radio's down.
废了没用了
It's dead. Counter that.
电磁脉冲干扰
Emp-burst.
看看今天这鬼地方会发生什么
Let's see how this day is going in this godforsaken desert.
你好
Yes, sir.
论诺克斯少校让我给你打电话
Major Lennox told me to pull the cord.
我知道
I know, sir.
那个...我...我现在在哪个国家
W-which, what country am I in right now?
美利坚
United states.
不不...不是  我就是从美利坚来的
No, no, not the united states. I'm from the united states,
鬼知道这是什么地方  四周都是羊
I'm in the middle of nowhere, surrounded by goats.
那是我们的好朋友盖勒威
Well, that was our good friend, Galloway.
看来  他有点不高兴
He's less than pleased.
怪了  我们联系不到自己人
How is it that we can't reach our men,
他却能在那片埃及沙漠里联系到我们
But he can reach me from some random egyptian desert?
没用
Nothing.
发求救信号  请求空中他方援助
Mike, put an sos, let the eye in the sky know we need some help.
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.
再放信号弹  好让那孩子找到我们
Pop some more flares so that the kid can find us.
他就是那儿  还有几里路
There he is. We got a couple of miles.
罗诺克斯的队伍拥有
Lennox's team has
最先进的量子通讯器材
the latest in quantum crypto gear.
谁能告诉我  为什么我们之间
Can somebody tell me
连简单的通信连接都不能够建立呢
Why we can't establish simple radio contact?
我们正尝试所有可用的频段和模式  长官
We're hailing them on every frequency and mode in the book, sir.
那个区域的卫星已经不能工作了
Our satellites in the area have gone blind.
正在整修中
We're working it, sir.
活见鬼
Dammit.
-情况不太正常  -说这个没用
- Something's not right - it doesn't add up.
联系约旦军方  看他们有什么情报
Contact the Jordanians, see what their assets they've got in the Area.
联络埃及萨拉姆将军
And get egypt's general Salaam,
请他派出无人机侦查那片领空
Ask him to clear some usv over-flights in egyptian airspace.
现在需要各方帮助看清状况  要快
We need an assist in confirming visuals now.
无人机起飞
Scramble predators now.
B1  起飞
B-1, rotate.
东边几英里吧
East on the mile that way.
来
Come here.
这边
This way.
-一个孤胆英雄  -别再说了
- One man... Alone... - Stop saying that.
-精忠报国却不受重用  -我的天
- Betrayed by the country he loves. - Oh my goodness,
我还在车里呢  你算不上孤胆
I'm in the car, okay? You're not alone.
放松  小子你有点进步
Just relax, you're looking nice well.
我觉得...他们已经被甩掉了
I...I don't think he's still following us.
那是你一厢情愿
That's what you think.
主人  很遗憾告诉您个坏消息
Master, sorry to be the bearer of bad news,
他们把擎天柱运来了
But the soldiers brought the body of prime.
那男孩肯定找到能量源了
The boy must have the matrix.
不能让他接近擎天柱
We cannot let him reach Optimus.
霸天虎们
Decepticons!
开始攻击
Begin our assault!
遭到袭击
We got incoming!
我方遭到空袭
We got a whole load of flight coming our way!
-多少  -预计十三架
- How many? - We got 13 to count.
不吉利  不吉利啊
This ain't good. This ain't good.
这场仗可真是难打呀
We 'bout to get our asses whooped.
那些霸天虎正在寻找山姆
Alright, those decepticons are searching for Sam.
不管那孩子找到什么
Whatever he has,
他认为那东西能够救活擎天柱
He thinks it'll bring Optimus back to life.
我们任务就是找到山姆  带他去擎天柱那里
So our mission is to find him and get him to Optimus.
好  我们由左翼吸引火力
Alright, we're gonna draw fire from the left flag.
我需要侦察队
I need a scout team.
我带队  同阿尔茜和铁皮从中路上
We'll walk through the middle with Arcee and Ironhide.
当你们看到孩子
Alright, when you see the precious cargo,
就放绿色烟雾  然后回到柱子那边
I want you to pop green smoke and come back to those pillars.
我们打个伏击战
We'll have the ambush set.
好的  出发  快
Alright, let's go, move out!
-出发  -出发
- Move out! - Move out!
看过五七年那部经典枪战片吗
Did you see that film gunfire aero-kay karao?
-卡斯廷·科克·道格拉斯演的  -没有 怎么了
- Casting Kirk Douglas. - No, why?
我们和他们处境一样
Looks like we're right in the middle of it.
结局好吗
Is that good?
很多人都死了
Lot of people died.
-天啊  -隐蔽
- Oh, oh, oh... - Hide!
神呐
Oh my god!
█
大力神：霸天虎成员
七个挖地虎成员组成
山姆  山姆
Sam, Sam.
蹲下  蹲下
Get down, get down.
只说一遍  听好  我们要跑到擎天柱那
Once, it's clear, we'll run for Optimus
能跑多快跑多快
As fast we can, okay?
要是不行怎么办
And what if it doesn't work?
一定能行
This will work.
-要是万一不行呢  -一定行
- Yeah, but what if it doesn't? - It's gonna work.
一定能行
It'll work.
准备跳
Ready to show.
还有半英里
We got a half a mile.
大兵们应该不知道我们在这儿
I don't think the soldiers know we're here.
撤退
Fall back!
铁皮  到中间来
Ironhide, up for middle.
铁皮快走
Ironhide, move it.
走  快快快
Go! Go, go!
没路可逃  我们要被困死了
There's no way to go. We're gonna die!
听着  即便要死  也得像个爷们
Listen, we're going out. We're going out like men, understand?
你瞧这该死的大力神
Look at this motherf--
真够恶心的
Mean robots suck!
回来
Get back!
抓住了  被别吸进去
Grab it! Don't let go.
坚持住  老兄  我抓住了
Hang in, man, I got this.
我不想死
I don't wanna die.
抓住了  老兄  抓住了
Careful grip, boy. Careful grip.
他做到了  满嘴都是垃圾
He did. He got so waste.
知道山外有山  人外有人了吧
Who's your daddy now, huh?
啥都被他吞了...
He got all these...
最保命的地方就是他的下面
Well, the safe place is right under it.
跑到他脚底下去
Run it. Run for his feet!
让你吃我  我要砸烂你的脸
You're never eating me. I'm gonna bust your face up.
跟我斗  别不要脸了
Nobody's tested me. In your face!
算我一个  挡泥板
Take five, Mudflap.
天
Oh my god!
没人能惹得起双胞胎兄弟
Nobody messes with the twins.
我抓到你了
I got you.
老兄  你射到我的脸了
Ow, man, you shot me in the face!
-呆在下面  -对  呆在它下面
- Stay under it! - Yeah, stay under it.
狂暴  带人质
朱迪
Judy!
-山姆  -什么
- Sam! - What?
山姆
Sam!
山姆  山姆
Sam! Sam!
山姆
Sam!
-儿子  -爸
- Sam. - dad!
等等
Wait! Wait!
█
狂暴：霸天虎成员
卡特彼勒推土机
听着
Please listen--
快跑快跑
I want you to run! Run!
-爸别说了  -离开这儿
- Dad, just stop! - Get out of here.
-他们要的不是你们  是我  -跑
- They don't want you, they want me. - Just run!
天  等下
Oh god, wait!
-塞缪尔·威特维奇  -等下
- Samuel Witwicky. - wait.
你要的是这个  别伤害他们
This is what you want. You don't want 'em.
-快走  -拜托  别啰嗦了
- go! Go! - please, stop! Stop!
-你怎么不听...-赶紧走
- Why don't you... - Just get out of here!
别动
Just don't move.
我认识你
I know you.
快走  快走
Just go! Just go!
我知道你要的是我
And I know what, you need me.
看  因为我知道能量源
Because I know about the matrix.
-儿子别干傻事  -爸
- Don't do it. Sam, listen to me. - Please, dad.
他们还是会杀光我们的
They're gonna kill us all anyway.
看
Hey, hey. Look.
你要的东西就在这儿
This is what you want. I'm here.
大黄蜂
Bumblebee!
救命
Help!
杀了他  大黄蜂
Kill him, bee. Kill him.
快  进去
Come on, get in.
大黄蜂
Bee?
搞不懂是哪儿  反正还得跑
Hey! I don't know what's going on, but we gotta move.
-快  -肯定有条出路
- Run! - There's gotta be a way out of here.
跟紧了  到里面来
Buckle up, buckle up! Get in here.
大黄蜂
Bee! Bumblebee!
你要把我爸妈带到安全的地方  明白吗
You get them somewhere safe, alright?
你们到车里去  那里安全
You gotta get in the car. You can be safe.
不  现在还争什么争
No, listen to my discussion.
-你是我儿子对吧  -对
- You're my son, alright? - I know!
上阵父子兵
You're my son! We'll all go together.
咱爷俩一起去
Listen...we're all going together.
爸别说了  好吗  你们快上车
Dad, stop, okay? Get in the car.
大黄蜂会把你们带到安全的地方  只管跑
He's gonna get you to safety. You don't, you run.
别停下  也别躲  使劲跑  听懂了吗
You don't stop, you don't hide, you run. You hear what I'm saying?
一家人活着才能团聚
Okay? I'll find you when you're safe.
-不要  -爸  让我做该做的事
- No. - You gotta let me go, dad.
让我去吧
You'll have to let me go.
-必须的  -罗恩
- you have to. - ron.
罗恩  随他去吧
Ron, ron! Let him go.
一定要回来呀
Just come back!
-走  -走
- Come on! - Come on!
米凯拉  米凯拉
Mikaela, Mikaela!
-你跟我爸妈走  -我要和你一起
- Go with my parents. - I'm not gonna go with them.
-约旦援军到了  -有帮手了
- We got jordanians! - We got help!
没事吧大兵
You okay, soldier?
我们是来帮你的
We're gonna help you, soldier.
咱们还要军民同心打铁鸟呢
Let's get being moon and clear the birds!
别动  别动  先别动
Stay still, stay still. Don't move.
你还好吗  孩子
You alright, young man?
-有无线电吗  -有
- You have a radio? - Yes.
孩子  咱爷俩处的不错
Hey kid, it's been nice knowing you.
记住大叔为祖国所做的
Remember what I did for my country.
该我上场了
This is my moment.
你疯了
You're crazy!
预计2分钟内到达指定位置
Eta to station, two minutes.
-接在主屏上显示  -遵命  长官
- Put it on the main screen. - Sir, yes, sir.
无人机  1号
Predator's air-one.
糟糕  被包围了
Oh shit, it's a trick.
启动风暴行动
Commence operation firestorm. Send everyone.
-营救我方士兵  -我是总部
- Get those boys out of the ground. - This is 101 in strike Packages.
海军陆战队准备出发
Fast course river. Execute lightly.
-发现山姆  -快点  别磨蹭
- Spotted Sam. - Hurry, don't slow up!
铁皮
Ironhide!
跟我们到柱子那边  去找擎天柱
Follow us to the pillars. We'll take you to Optimus.
当心
Look out!
山姆  到柱子那边
Sam, get to the pillars!
走
Let's go.
天啊  看来金字塔下面就是机器
Oh god, this is it. The pyramids built right over the machine.
机器一旦被启动
They turn that machine on...
太阳就没了
No more sun.
那得先过我这关
Not on my watch.
我绝对不答应
-美军斯滕尼斯号  身份确认  -你们到底在哪儿
- Uss stennis, identify. - hey, where the hell are you?
在看气象频道吗
What, you're on a weather channel?
还是体育新闻  情景喜剧什么吗
Sports center, high-dreaming tv or something?
天上几百个卫星顶屁用
We get a pretty hundred satellites up there.
我们的人  都在哪儿
Where the hell are all our men?
请报上您的身份
Identify yourself.
你叫什么  水手
What is your name, sailor?
怀尔德  我是斯滕尼斯号航母的舰长
Wilder, captain of the uss john c. Stennis aircraft carrier.
好吧  怀尔德舰长
Okay, captain Wilder,
我是第七区特工头领西蒙·西蒙斯
This is agent Seymour Simmons, head of the sector seven.
现在一个外星来的合体机器人
There is a mother of all non-biologicals
正准备摧毁太阳
Getting ready to blow up our sun.
你是要继续跟我争论是否有许可
You want to have fooled down about my lack of clearance,
还是去拯救亿万人的性命呢
Or you want to help save a gazillion lives?
好吧  西蒙斯  我听你的
Alright, agent Simmons. I'm listening.
海湾以西五公里
Five klicks.West of the gulf.
现在大力神正在摧毁金字塔
We got ourselves a dalion remodelling a pyramid.
唯一的希望就是那门轨道炮
I want hopes of prototype weapon pull a rail gun.
那有关国家机密
That's classified.
别跟我谈什么国家机密
Don't talk to me about classified, alright?
如果你的船到了海湾
Now if you've got a battleship in the gulf
就叫他们准备发射轨道炮
You tell him to ready that weapon!
呼叫驱逐舰  基德号
Contact destroyer, uss kit.
这里  过来
This way! Move it!
到这儿来
What you need is there.
走走走
Let's go! Go!
把无线电给我
Give me your talk. Come on.
爱普斯接着
Epps!
我们请求空中支援
Right now, we need air support.
20英里处有架航母发出信号
That ship's in contact. 20 miles--
保持联系  艾尔法号出发
Grid on contact. Proceed 88, alpha sierra.
斯特尼090号  发射2000发导弹
Uss stenin 0-9-0, you are approved to drop a 2,000--
-情况如何  -刚发生爆炸
- What you got? - A detonator, sir.
六点方向  他们跑向柱子那边了
They're 600 minutes away and they're heading right for the pillars.
好的
Alright.
孩子马上出现
Precious cargo's coming.
走
Move!
山姆
Sam!
发现山姆
Spotted Sam.
快
Come on!
两两火力掩护  12点方向  保护那两个人
2-2, covering fire. Two civilians, twelve o'clock.
掩护我们
Cover for us.
保持火力  我们正在营救那两个人
Okay, air strike. We'll rescue the civilians.
走  起来
Come on. Get up!
来
Come on!
进来
Get in here.
瞧瞧这是谁呀
Oh look who showed up.
把我们调这儿来  你最好给个充分的理由
You better have a good reason for us to be here.
擎天柱呢
Where's Optimus?
他就在院子那边
He's right over there, across the courtyard.
那我就去找他
I got to get to him right now.
不行  空袭正在逼近
No, we got an air strike coming.
我必须马上见到他
I have to get to him right now.
过来  过来
Come here, b-back.
老子来啦
Incoming!
瞧瞧我天火的英姿吧
Behold to the only jetfire!
让敌人尝尝我的威力
Now let me show you how we brought them pain in my day.
老啦老啦  不顶用了
Too old for this crap.
加油
Keep going.
15分钟内解决战斗
15 minutes of fighting.
我就在大力神的裤裆下面
I am directly below the enemy's scrotum.
海平面25.7米  北纬29.32度
25.7 metres above sea level,29.32 north.
-发射轨道520  5点方向  -目标锁定
- Field track, 5-2, 0500 o'clock. - Target acquired.
双轨放射
Killing track two.
保持锁定  发射
Lock. Fire.
B1轰炸机接近目标时间  30秒
B-1, stand on my target. 30 seconds...
所有的人都要听我指挥
We're gonna make a break for the beast on my command, okay?
一定要跟着我走
You guys stick with me, you understand?
你们跟在我身后
You stay on my ass.
希望那些F16能打准点
Hope these f-16s got good aim.
为啥这么说
Yeah, why is that?
我告诉他们橘红色烟雾是打击目标
I told them to hit the orange smoke.
你是说橘红色的烟雾吗
You mean that orange smoke?
对不起  我扔得太近了
It wasn't my best toss, okay?
-跑  -跑
- Run! - Run!
来了
Incoming!
快
Come on.
去死
Die!
山姆
Sam!
停火
Hold your fire!
山姆
Sam!
让开  腹压抢救
Get out! Get me an evac.
这能救活他吗
Can't you do something?
-儿子  -儿子
- Sam! Sam... - Sam!
来  我们得到旁边来
Come on, we got to move. We got to move! Come on!
山姆
Sammy!
准备  电击  准备  电击
Clear! Take a shot. Clear! Take a shot.
1  2  3
One, two, three.
再来
Do it again.
山姆
Sam!
听我说  我爱你  我需要你
Okay, listen to my voice. I love you and I need you.
回到我身边  求你了  山姆  我爱你
Please, please come back to me. Sam, please! I love you!
我死了吗
Am I dead?
我们一直在注视你  很久了
We have been watching you. A long, long time.
你为擎天柱而战斗
You have fought for Optimus,
我们唯一的后人  英勇无比  不怕牺牲
Our last descendant, with courage and with sacrifice.
具有领袖气魄
The virtues of a leader.
值得我们将秘密托付给你
A leader worthy of our secret.
领袖之源不是被发现的
The matrix of leadership is not found.
而是通过努力得来的
It is earned.
回到擎天柱身边
Return now to Optimus,
将能量源和他的火种融合
Merge the matrix with his spark.
这就是你一生的使命
It is, and always has been, your destiny.
山姆
Sam.
我爱你
I love you.
孩子  你为我回来
Boy, you returned for me.
一个活生生的领袖
A living prime!
真难以置信
I don't believe it.
能量源是我的
My matrix.
起来  起来  起来
Get up, get up, get up, get up.
站起来 擎天柱
Get up, prime!
-不不不  -他正在开启机器
- Oh, no. - He's turned on the machine.
阻止他  快起来
You gotta stop him. Get up!
擎天柱
Optimus!
堕落金刚  我的主人
Fallen, my master.
其他金刚弟兄都不能阻挡我
My brothers could not stop me from this.
-对  -现在 太阳是我的了
- Yes. - Now I claim your sun.
敌方目标  金字塔顶
Enemy target, top of pyramid.
预备  发射
Engage, engage, engage.
很快我们的能力会更加强大
In moments, we'll be at siren strength.
我这辈子没干过有意义的事
I never did a thing worth doing until now.
擎天柱  收下我的火种
Optimus, take my parts.
这能量之强大  你无法预料
And you'll have a power you've never known.
完成你的使命
Fulfill your destiny.
摇摆  上电  救护车  拆卸黑鸟
Jolt, electrify! Ratchet，unset the birds!
出发
Let's roll.
火力瞄准金字塔
Fire. Take it off to the pyramid!
这个星球将永远陷入黑暗中
This planet will be dark forever.
像你兄弟一样死去吧
Die like your brother.
他们也是你的兄弟
They were your brothers too.
老大
First gra--
你选错星球了
You picked the wrong planet!
尝我一拳
Give me your face.
你失败了
I rise. You fall.
不
No. No.
我不想劝您做胆小鬼  主人
Not to call you a coward, master, but sometimes,
不过好死不如赖活着
Cowards do survive.
这不算完
This isn't over.
经历了这么多你才想说爱我吗
You took all of this for you to tell me that you love me.
你先说的
You said it first.
谢谢你  山姆  你救了我的命
Thank you, Sam, for saving my life.
别客气
You're welcome.
谢谢你信任我
Thank you for believing in me.
我们的种族  因一段遗忘的过去团结起来
Our races united by a history long forgotten.
齐心协力面对未来
And a future we shall face together.
我是擎天柱  在此发出倡议
I am Optimus prime, and I send this message
让这段历史流传下去
So that our past will always be remembered.
记忆若能永存   生命才能不息
For in those memories, we live on.
欢迎你来听课  爱因斯坦教授
So glad you join us, professor Einstein.
对  最近有点忙
Yeah，I am kinds of busy.
好了
OK.